<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>European Union Center Events</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/1169</link>
        <description>A calendar of events sponsored or attended by the European Union Center.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Hispanic Linguistics Symposium</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1169/32633823</link>
            <category>Symposium</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1169/32633823</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Spanish and Portuguese will host the Hispanic Linguistics Symposium from September 24 &amp;ndash; 27, 2015. HLS is an annual conference with a focus on theoretical and applied linguistics in Spanish and Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lecture: Cosmopolitan Language Systems in the Mediterranean</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1169/32574279</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1169/32574279</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 17:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karla Mallette studies communications between literary traditions in the medieval Mediterranean&amp;mdash;especially Arabic and the Romance vernaculars&amp;mdash;and the way that we remember that history today. Her first book, &lt;em&gt;The Kingdom of Sicily, 1100-1250: A Literary History&lt;/em&gt; (University of Pennsylvania Press, 2005), traced the transition between Arabic and Italian literary traditions in medieval Sicily; her second, &lt;em&gt;European Modernity and the Arab Mediterranean&lt;/em&gt; (University of Pennsylvania Press, 2010), focused on a southern European tradition of scholarship that identifies the origins of modernity in the contact between Islamic and Christian civilizations in the medieval Mediterranean. Her current project, tentatively titled&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Lives of the Great Languages: Cosmopolitan Languages in the Medieval Mediterranean&lt;/em&gt;, studies the strategies that language uses to transcend the boundaries that language creates. By profiling two pre-modern cosmopolitan languages, Arabic and Latin, and acknowledging the emergent cosmopolitan languages of the twenty-first century, the book contextualizes and defamiliarizes the national language system of European modernity. She has published essays on medieval translations of Aristotelian philosophy, framed narratives, European Orientalism, and Mediterranean Studies, in addition to Italian literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>