<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>National and International Scholarships Program</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/1826</link>
        <description>This calendar lists promotional sessions and deadline dates for nationally competitive scholarships that are coordinated through the National and International Scholarships Program. http://www.topscholars.illinois.edu/</description>
        <item>
            <title>Marshall, Gates, Schwarzman Scholarships Priority Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615705</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615705</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The priority deadline for the Gates, Marshall and Schwarzman Scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions please contact the National and International Scholarships Program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fulbright Priority Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615706</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615706</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The priority deadline for the Fulbright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions please contact the National and International Scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rhodes, Marshall, Mitchell, and Schwarzman Campus Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615702</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615702</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Campus deadline&amp;nbsp;for the Gates, Rhodes, Marshall, Mitchell, or Schwarzman Scholarships-all scholarship materials must be submitted to the National and International Scholarships Program by 12:00 pm (noon)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Luce Scholars Program Information Information Session</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633647</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633647</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National and International Scholarships Program is offering a two-day informational event about the Luce Scholars Program. &amp;nbsp;The Luce is a one-year internship after graduation in Asia or Southeast-Asia, and designed specifically for students who do not have much prior experience in that region. &amp;nbsp;On August 27th, our office will offer an informational overview session, including advice from previous Illinois Luce recipients, followed on August 28th with a workshop designed to help students begin to craft their personal statements. &amp;nbsp;All events will be held in 514 IUB. &amp;nbsp;August 27th 3:30-4:30 is the informational session and discussion with a former Luce Scholar. August 28th 3:30-4:30 is the workshop on how to craft a Personal Statement. &amp;nbsp;More information about the Luce can be found here: &lt;a href="http://www.topscholars.illinois.edu/prestigious/luce.html"&gt;http://www.topscholars.illinois.edu/prestigious/luce.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Luce Scholars Program Workshop</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633648</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633648</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National and International Scholarships Program is offering a Luce Scholars Workshop designed to help students begin to craft their personal statements. &amp;nbsp;The workshop will be held on August 28th from 3:30-4:30 in IUB Room 514. &amp;nbsp;More information about the Luce can be found here: &lt;a href="http://www.topscholars.illinois.edu/prestigious/luce.html"&gt;http://www.topscholars.illinois.edu/prestigious/luce.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fulbright Campus Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615704</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615704</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Fulbright Campus Deadline-all materials must be submitted by 12:00 pm (noon)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gilman Scholarship Information Session</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633816</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633816</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gilman International Scholarship Program provides awards of $5,000 (plus up to a $3,000 supplement for critical languages) for U.S. citizen undergraduate students to pursue summer, semester, or academic-year study abroad opportunities in other countries. This is a need based award, and to be eligible, students currently must be receiving a Federal Pell Grant. &amp;nbsp;The National and International Scholarships Program is willing to assist in reviewing your scholarship application material, in fact, we welcome the opportunity to help make your application more competitive! &amp;nbsp;As such, we are offering a two-day informational event about the Gilman Scholarship. September 3rd from 3:30-4:30 is an informational session and alumni Q&amp;amp;A. &amp;nbsp;September 4th between 3:30-4:30 is a workshop on how to craft your application essays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gilman Scholarship Workshop</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633817</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633817</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National and International Scholarships Program is willing to assist in reviewing your Gilman scholarship application material in fact, we welcome the opportunity to help make your application more competitive! &amp;nbsp;As such, we are offering a workshop designed to help students begin to craft their application statements. &amp;nbsp;It will be September 4th between 3:30-4:30 in IUB Room 514.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gates Campus Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615871</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32615871</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Campus deadline for the Gates Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions please contact the National and International Scholarships Program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Luce Scholars Program Campus Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633819</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633819</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Luce Scholars Program Campus Deadline-application materials must be turned into the National and International Scholarships Program by 12:00 pm (noon)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Churchill Scholarship Campus Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633820</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633820</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The campus deadline for the Churchill scholarship-All scholarship materials need to be turned into the National and International Scholarships Program by 12:00 pm (noon)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Truman Scholarship Information Session</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633825</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633825</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Illini who want to change the world: &amp;nbsp;The campus is currently looking for exciting juniors* to nominate for the prestigious Harry S. Truman Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you bothered by an issue and trying to make changes to address a problem? &amp;nbsp;The Truman program is looking for the academically strong student who has a passion for public service. Evaluators look for leadership ability, potential for influencing public policies, community service and extracurricular involvement, strong academic performance, and potential to perform well in a graduate school program. It awards $30,000 merit-based scholarships to U.S. citizen college students who wish to attend graduate school in preparation for careers in public service. &amp;nbsp;Public service includes a wide array of career possibilities, such as public health; local, state, or federal government; educational policy; international relations; conservation; and environmental protection. Candidates should be able to demonstrate leadership experiences in campus and community service activities. Truman Scholars have pursued many fields of study, such as agriculture, engineering, economics, education, government, history, international relations, law, political science, public administration, and public health. Scholars are required to work in public service for three of the seven years following completion of a Foundation funded graduate degree program as a condition of receiving funding. &amp;nbsp;The University of Illinois may nominate up to four students for the Truman Scholarship. The campus deadline is November 12, 2015 to be considered. If you are interested in applying, please plan to attend our informational sessions. &amp;nbsp;On Thursday Oct. 15 from 3:30-4:30 there will be an information session &amp;amp; discussion w/ former Truman Scholar in IUB Room 504. &amp;nbsp;On Friday Oct. 16 from 3:30-4:30 there will be a workshop on how to craft a Truman Application in IUB Room 514. &amp;nbsp;Additional information about the award may be found at: http://www.topscholars.illinois.edu/prestigious/truman.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*For the Truman Scholarship, a "Junior" is defined as someone either in their third and final year of undergraduate study, or someone planning to graduate between December 2016 and August 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Truman Scholarship Workshop</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633826</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633826</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to help get you started on your Truman Scholarship application. Aspiring nominees will receive tips on application components and leave with some text crafted for many of the sections of a Truman application.&amp;nbsp;The Truman program is looking for the academically strong student who has a passion for public service. Evaluators look for leadership ability, potential for influencing public policies, community service and extracurricular involvement, strong academic performance, and potential to perform well in a graduate school program. It awards $30,000 merit-based scholarships to U.S. citizen college students who wish to attend graduate school in preparation for careers in public service. &amp;nbsp;Public service includes a wide array of career possibilities, such as public health; local, state, or federal government; educational policy; international relations; conservation; and environmental protection. Candidates should be able to demonstrate leadership experiences in campus and community service activities. Truman Scholars have pursued many fields of study, such as agriculture, engineering, economics, education, government, history, international relations, law, political science, public administration, and public health. Scholars are required to work in public service for three of the seven years following completion of a Foundation funded graduate degree program as a condition of receiving funding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Goldwater Scholarship Information Session</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633992</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633992</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National and International Scholarships Program is offering a two-day event about the Barry M. Goldwater Scholarship. The Goldwater Scholarship offers $7,500 to either sophomores or juniors in STEM disciplines who aim to pursue a Ph.D. in their field. &amp;nbsp;On October 22, attendants will receive an overview of the scholarship as well as have a chance to talk with a former Goldwater Scholarship recipient from Illinois. &amp;nbsp;On October 23, the Scholarships Program will offer a workshop on how to write a competitive scholarship packet. &amp;nbsp;Students are encouraged to attend both events. &amp;nbsp;All events will be held in 514 IUB. &amp;nbsp;Thursday, October 22 from 3:30-4:30 is the overview and discussion with a former Goldwater Scholar and Friday, October 23 from 3:30-4:30 is the workshop on how to craft a competitive application packet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Goldwater Scholarship Workshop</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633993</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633993</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National and International Scholarships Program is offering an event about the Barry M. Goldwater Scholarship. The Goldwater Scholarship offers $7,500 to either sophomores or juniors in STEM disciplines who aim to pursue a Ph.D. in their field. &amp;nbsp;This workshop will provide tips and help students get started on their actual applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Boren Undergraduate Scholarship Information Session</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633996</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633996</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Illinois will be hosting informational sessions on National Security Education Program Boren undergraduate study abroad scholarships. &amp;nbsp;Participants will receive information about the program and converse with an Illinois alumni recipient. &amp;nbsp;The campus application deadline is in January 2016 for any semester or year of study between May 2016 and May 2017. Students are encouraged to begin application drafts prior to leaving for winter break. &amp;nbsp;The Boren provides study abroad scholarships of $6,000-$20,000 for a full academic year or $4,000-$10,000 for a semester. Science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) students also have the option of applying for summer-only programs of eight weeks or more. All scholarships may be used for U.S. citizens to study in Asia, Africa, Central &amp;amp; Eastern Europe, Latin America, or the Middle East on almost any study abroad program. These are merit-based scholarships (approximately 1 in 5 eligible applicants receive awards). In order to receive the scholarship, award winners must enter into a service agreement requiring that they attempt to work in a paid position for the federal government in an area related to national security&amp;mdash;generally the Departments of State, Defense, Homeland Security, or the Intelligence Community within three years of graduation (deferrals possible/encouraged for graduate study). Working for USAID or tenure in the Peace Corps counts in the service requirement. Winners also receive priority-hiring status. &amp;nbsp;The Boren information session will be held on October 29th from 3:30-4:30 in IUB room 514 and the Boren workshop will be held on October 30th from 3:30-4:30 in IUB room 514. &amp;nbsp;For more information on the Boren you can visit &lt;a href="http://topscholars.illinois.edu/prestigious/nsep.html"&gt;http://topscholars.illinois.edu/prestigious/nsep.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Boren Undergraduate Scholarship Workshop</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633998</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633998</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Illinois will be hosting an event on National Security Education Program Boren undergraduate study abroad scholarships. &amp;nbsp;This workshop will provide tips and help students get started on their actual applications. The campus application deadline is January 2016 for any semester or year of study between May 2016 and May 2017. Students are encouraged to begin application drafts prior to leaving for winter break. &amp;nbsp;The Boren provides study abroad scholarships of $6,000-$20,000 for a full academic year or $4,000-$10,000 for a semester. Science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) students also have the option of applying for summer-only programs of eight weeks or more. All scholarships may be used for U.S. citizens to study in Asia, Africa, Central &amp;amp; Eastern Europe, Latin America, or the Middle East on almost any study abroad program. These are merit-based scholarships (approximately 1 in 5 eligible applicants receive awards). In order to receive the scholarship, award winners must enter into a service agreement requiring that they attempt to work in a paid position for the federal government in an area related to national security&amp;mdash;generally the Departments of State, Defense, Homeland Security, or the Intelligence Community within three years of graduation (deferrals possible/encouraged for graduate study). Working for USAID or tenure in the Peace Corps counts in the service requirement. Winners also receive priority-hiring status. &amp;nbsp;This workshop is intended to help you get started on your application for the Boren Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Beinecke Scholarship Information Session</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633999</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32633999</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 15:30:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a high-achieving junior and are planning to attend graduate school after graduation, but have concerns about being able to afford it, consider applying for the Beinecke Scholarship. The National and International Scholarships Program has planned two sessions to assist students towards earning this $34,000 award. On Thursday, November 5, we will be conducting an informational session, including a question and answer period with an Illini recipient, from 3:30-4:30 in IUB room 514 and on November 6, a Beinecke workshop from 3:30-4:30 in IUB room 514 to help students get started on their actual applications. &amp;nbsp;The Beinecke Foundation is looking for students who have demonstrated superior standards of intellectual ability, scholastic achievement, and personal promise during their undergraduate years. The program seeks to encourage and enable highly motivated U.S. citizen juniors to pursue graduate studies in the arts, humanities, and social sciences. Each scholar receives $4,000 immediately prior to entering graduate school and an additional $30,000 while attending graduate school. Preference is given to candidates for whom the awarding of significant financial aid would increase the likelihood of the student's being able to attend graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Beinecke Scholarship Workshop</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32634000</link>
            <category>student info</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32634000</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 15:30:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a high-achieving junior and are planning to attend graduate school after graduation, but have concerns about being able to afford it, consider applying for the Beinecke Scholarship. &amp;nbsp;On Friday, November 6 from 3:30-4:30 we will be presenting a hands-on workshop to assist in crafting your materials for the award. &amp;nbsp;The Beinecke Foundation is looking for students who have demonstrated superior standards of intellectual ability, scholastic achievement, and personal promise during their undergraduate years. The program seeks to encourage and enable highly motivated U.S. citizen juniors to pursue graduate studies in the arts, humanities, and social sciences. Each scholar receives $4,000 immediately prior to entering graduate school and an additional $30,000 while attending graduate school. Preference is given to candidates for whom the awarding of significant financial aid would increase the likelihood of the student's being able to attend graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Truman Scholarship Campus Deadline</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32634182</link>
            <category>student deadline</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/1826/32634182</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 12:00:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Truman Scholarship campus deadline-all scholarship materials need to be submitted to the National and International Scholarships Program by 12:00 pm (noon)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>