<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Technology Entrepreneur Center - Compele</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/2274</link>
        <description>This is the compete calendar for the Technology Entrepreneur Center.</description>
        <item>
            <title>ELLC Roundtable</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2274/32138196</link>
            <category>Special Events</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2274/32138196</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This program was created in 2012 by the Innovation Living-Learning Community at the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign in order to give leaders of ELLCs the opportunity to gather in one spot for shared discussion and networking opportunities. Staff from campuses that are considering starting ELLCs are also welcome and encouraged to join us! The content of the Roundtable is very participant-driven, with lots of opportunities to explore program successes and help answer each other&amp;rsquo;s questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Midwest Engineering Entrepreneurship Network (M.E.E.N.)</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2274/32138197</link>
            <category>Special Events</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2274/32138197</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In 2011, TEC and CFE recognized the value in establishing an organization that would provide a forum for sharing best practices and methods for overcoming challenges unique to Midwest engineering entrepreneurship centers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you should attend:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how other schools are implementing Lean Launch Pad (LLP) in the curriculum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See how LLP is used to pull technology out of the labs and into the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find how other universities are breaking down the educational siloes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present a best practice in Engineering Entrepreneurship from your organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe a challenge you are having that the MEEN network may be able to help with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing and exploring new ideas and tackling the common problems we all face. We hope that you plan to attend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no registration fee to attend this event, but participants are responsible for providing their own transportation and accommodations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;*This conference is open to University administration, faculty and staff.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past participants include: Penn State, Wayne State, Illinois Institute of Technology, Michigan Technological University, Northwestern University, University of Wisconsin-Madison, University of Akron, University of Iowa, University of Michigan, University of Minnesota and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>