<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>College of Engineering, All Events</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/2568</link>
        <description>This calendar includes all of the calendars for the College of Engineering.</description>
        <item>
            <title>IT No Change Period in effect</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/31225359</link>
            <category>Academic</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/31225359</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The CITES No Change period is designed to minimize the number of technical disruptions that might occur around final exams. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beginning on Reading Day and continuing a few days past the end of finals, CITES tries to make no technical changes to hardware or software that might disrupt the availability of the campus network, data storage, web sites or any of the software-based services that CITES provides to campus. Changes or updates will only be made by CITES for emergency purposes during the No Change period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Faculty input meeting on regional Big Data Hub</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32712115</link>
            <category>Meeting</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32712115</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Science Foundation is launching a 10-year effort to create partnerships around Big Data and the management infrastructure for Big Data. The partnerships and infrastructure are expected to evolve around four regions (South, Northeast, Midwest and West) and NSF is calling for the creation of four Regional Innovation Big Data Hubs. Phase 1 of this effort began with a solicitation (http://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2015/nsf15562/nsf15562.htm) in which NSF expects to fund up to four proposals (one from each region).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Illinois is directing the effort for the Midwest Regional Big Data Innovation Hub with Ed Seidel, Director of NCSA and Klara Nahrstedt, Director of the Coordinated Science Laboratory in the College of Engineering, as leads. Our proposal is being written in collaboration with many organizations across the Midwest covering the broad Big Data challenges of the Midwest, which then academia, industry, foundations, and non-profit organizations can assist to solve. More information will be available as the process unfolds at https://bdhub.info/&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At Illinois, Klara and Ed are seeking knowledge and input for the proposal from researchers who use Big Data in their domains and who would like to see a broad regional and national alliance develop solutions to the challenges of Big Data. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To facilitate researchers' input at Illinois, Klara and Ed are organizing two informational meetings on our campus to inform interested faculty about the possibilities, including ways to contribute and provide input to the proposal and to join the Big Data alliance in Midwest (and nationally). In both meetings, they will present NSF goals for this Big Data initiative and the process Illinois will follow in writing the Midwest Regional Big Data Hub proposal, followed by open discussion. The research areas addressed in these two meetings will not be identical, but rather will cover distinct topics as outlined below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first Big Data Hub Informational Talk is scheduled from 9-11 a.m. Wednesday, May 13, in the Institute for Genomic Biology's Room 612. Topical discussion will address potential faculty participation and contributions in the areas of Food-Water-Energy Nexus, Genomics, Bioinformatics, Life Sciences, Health Sciences and Digital Agriculture. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second Big Data Hub Informational Talk is scheduled for 1-3 p.m. Thursday, May 21, in the NCSA Auditorium. Topical discussion will be in the areas of Smart Cities, Advanced Manufacturing, Network Science, Transportation, IT Tools and Services, and Data Science. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope to see you at one of the Informational Talks and to foster broad participation of Illinois faculty in creating Big Data partnerships and infrastructures both across the Midwest and nationally.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have questions, please contact Kandace Turner-Jones at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:ktrnrjns@illinois.edu"&gt;ktrnrjns@illinois.edu&lt;/a&gt; or 217-300-2042.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Brown Bag: Office of Technology Management</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32541488</link>
            <category>Seminar</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32541488</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Office of Technology Management (OTM) at the University of Illinois in Urbana-Champaign manages intellectual property resulting from the research activities at the univesity. We work with units across campus to help identify, protect, license or otherwise promote research &amp;nbsp;innovations for public use. Svetlana Sowers&amp;nbsp; from OTM and a representative from University Counsel will present a brief overview of OTM services, will discuss how our office can serve NCSA )including promoting and disseminating works developed at NCSA), and will be there to answer your questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Book signing with Walt Robb</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32703971</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32703971</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Walt Robb earned his PhD in chemical engineering from the University of Illinois in 1951 (in three years) and joined GE as a young researcher. As the CT scanning revolution got underway and MRI technology took off, Robb oversaw the business expand from a break-even, $100 million business to a highly profitable and growing enterprise. In 1993, President Bill Clinton presented him with a National Medal of Technology and Innovation for his foresight and leadership in the MRI and CT imaging industry. He is a recipient of the university's Alumni Achievement Award and the President&amp;rsquo;s Medallion. Robb will be at Roger Adams Laboratory May 14 for a book signing and reception. His new book, &amp;ldquo;Taking Risks: Getting Ahead in Business and Life,&amp;rdquo; offers advice for students and new graduates, technology start-ups, and managers at all levels. He also shares insights on his 20 years of working under fellow UI graduate and GE&amp;rsquo;s longtime CEO Jack Welch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dean's International Graduation Reception</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32414036</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32414036</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 16:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Dean Andreas Cangellaris invites the families of graduating Engineering students to join him for a reception honoring international BS, MS &amp;amp; PhD graduates. The reception will be hosted the evening prior to Engineering Commencement and graduates will be able to meet with College and Department representatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dean's International Graduation Reception</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32637080</link>
            <category>Special Event</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32637080</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 16:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;The Dean's International Graduation Reception is scheduled from 4:30-6:30 p.m. May 15 in the Kavita and Lalit Bahl Meeting Room, 3002 ECE Building.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please join Dean Andreas Cangellaris for a reception honoring international BS, MS and PhD graduates. The reception will be hosted the evening prior to Engineering Commencement, and graduates will be able to meet with college and department representatives. Students and their families are welcome to attend. To RSVP, please follow the link below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LINK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://engineering.illinois.edu/engage/events/international.html"&gt;http://engineering.illinois.edu/engage/events/international.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Campuswide May Commencement Ceremony</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32204349</link>
            <category>General Event</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32204349</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;For more information on the May Commencement Ceremony, please visit http://commencement.illinois.edu/students/index.html.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Commencement</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/21388398</link>
            <category>Academic</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/21388398</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Campuswide Commencement</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32440133</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32440133</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 09:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The campuswide Commencement ceremony is the official University of Illinois academic ceremony at which the Chancellor presides and the President confers degrees. Doctoral degree candidates are individually recognized. Bachelor's and Master's degree recipients stand as a group at their seats and are recognized by college. This is a dignified ceremony held in Memorial Stadium that lasts about two and a half hours. Academic attire is required. This ceremony will be held on Saturday, May 16, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Physics Convocation &amp; Reception</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32599207</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32599207</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>MechSE Graduation Reception</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32419990</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32419990</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Graduation Brunch and Awards Celebration</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32416092</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32416092</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 10:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Look for details to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2015 Graduation Brunch</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32682551</link>
            <category>Special Event</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32682551</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 10:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to all of our students who are graduating - you are invited to ECE ILLINOIS' Graduation Brunch, scheduled for 10:30 a.m. Sunday, May 17, at the Hilton Garden Inn, 1501 S. Neil St., Champaign.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brunch will be served at 11 a.m. and a brief program will begin at 11:30 a.m.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brunch is free for graduating students and is $15 per registered guest. Please register by May 11 using the link below. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Each graduating student will receive a gift from the department and the chance to sign the Class of 2015 banner at this event.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Students who are unable to attend may still pick up their gifts and sign the banner in 2120 ECE Building beginning April 29.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Questions? Contact Assistant Director of Student Relations Audrey LeGrande at &lt;a href="mailto:alegrand@illinois.edu"&gt;alegrand@illinois.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://ece.illinois.edu/brunch"&gt;ece.illinois.edu/brunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>ECE Graduation Brunch</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32419993</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32419993</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 10:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>MechSE Graduation Brunch</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32523562</link>
            <category>Special Topics</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32523562</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 11:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a celebration to recognize your achievement of graduating from one of the top engineering programs in the nation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>MatSE Graduation Lunch</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32692810</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32692810</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 11:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Materials Science and Engineering invites May 2015&amp;nbsp;graduates and their families to a Graduation Luncheon. Graduates will receive a total of three complimentary tickets--this includes&amp;nbsp;the ticket for the graduate's lunch. Additional tickets may be purchased for $10 each.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>MatSE Graduation Lunch</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32420005</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32420005</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 11:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Materials Science and Engineering Graduation Lunch</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32397644</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32397644</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 11:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>CEE Graduation Reception</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32691496</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32691496</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Engineering at Illinois Commencement Ceremony #1</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32442430</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2568/32442430</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 16:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The 4:30pm ceremony will include the following departments/degrees: Computer Science, Electrical and Computer Engineering (Electrical Engineering, Computer Engineering, Electrical and Computer Engineering), Industrial and Enterprise Systems Engineering (Industrial Engineering and General Engineering), Materials Science and Engineering&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>