<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ECE ILLINOIS Calendar</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/2622</link>
        <description>Departmental events</description>
        <item>
            <title>Faculty input meeting on regional Big Data Hub</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32712115</link>
            <category>Meeting</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32712115</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Science Foundation is launching a 10-year effort to create partnerships around Big Data and the management infrastructure for Big Data. The partnerships and infrastructure are expected to evolve around four regions (South, Northeast, Midwest and West) and NSF is calling for the creation of four Regional Innovation Big Data Hubs. Phase 1 of this effort began with a solicitation (http://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2015/nsf15562/nsf15562.htm) in which NSF expects to fund up to four proposals (one from each region).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Illinois is directing the effort for the Midwest Regional Big Data Innovation Hub with Ed Seidel, Director of NCSA and Klara Nahrstedt, Director of the Coordinated Science Laboratory in the College of Engineering, as leads. Our proposal is being written in collaboration with many organizations across the Midwest covering the broad Big Data challenges of the Midwest, which then academia, industry, foundations, and non-profit organizations can assist to solve. More information will be available as the process unfolds at https://bdhub.info/&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At Illinois, Klara and Ed are seeking knowledge and input for the proposal from researchers who use Big Data in their domains and who would like to see a broad regional and national alliance develop solutions to the challenges of Big Data. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To facilitate researchers' input at Illinois, Klara and Ed are organizing two informational meetings on our campus to inform interested faculty about the possibilities, including ways to contribute and provide input to the proposal and to join the Big Data alliance in Midwest (and nationally). In both meetings, they will present NSF goals for this Big Data initiative and the process Illinois will follow in writing the Midwest Regional Big Data Hub proposal, followed by open discussion. The research areas addressed in these two meetings will not be identical, but rather will cover distinct topics as outlined below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first Big Data Hub Informational Talk is scheduled from 9-11 a.m. Wednesday, May 13, in the Institute for Genomic Biology's Room 612. Topical discussion will address potential faculty participation and contributions in the areas of Food-Water-Energy Nexus, Genomics, Bioinformatics, Life Sciences, Health Sciences and Digital Agriculture. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second Big Data Hub Informational Talk is scheduled for 1-3 p.m. Thursday, May 21, in the NCSA Auditorium. Topical discussion will be in the areas of Smart Cities, Advanced Manufacturing, Network Science, Transportation, IT Tools and Services, and Data Science. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope to see you at one of the Informational Talks and to foster broad participation of Illinois faculty in creating Big Data partnerships and infrastructures both across the Midwest and nationally.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have questions, please contact Kandace Turner-Jones at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:ktrnrjns@illinois.edu"&gt;ktrnrjns@illinois.edu&lt;/a&gt; or 217-300-2042.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dean's International Graduation Reception</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32637080</link>
            <category>Special Event</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32637080</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 16:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;The Dean's International Graduation Reception is scheduled from 4:30-6:30 p.m. May 15 in the Kavita and Lalit Bahl Meeting Room, 3002 ECE Building.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please join Dean Andreas Cangellaris for a reception honoring international BS, MS and PhD graduates. The reception will be hosted the evening prior to Engineering Commencement, and graduates will be able to meet with college and department representatives. Students and their families are welcome to attend. To RSVP, please follow the link below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LINK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://engineering.illinois.edu/engage/events/international.html"&gt;http://engineering.illinois.edu/engage/events/international.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2015 Graduation Brunch</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32682551</link>
            <category>Special Event</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32682551</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 10:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to all of our students who are graduating - you are invited to ECE ILLINOIS' Graduation Brunch, scheduled for 10:30 a.m. Sunday, May 17, at the Hilton Garden Inn, 1501 S. Neil St., Champaign.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brunch will be served at 11 a.m. and a brief program will begin at 11:30 a.m.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brunch is free for graduating students and is $15 per registered guest. Please register by May 11 using the link below. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Each graduating student will receive a gift from the department and the chance to sign the Class of 2015 banner at this event.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Students who are unable to attend may still pick up their gifts and sign the banner in 2120 ECE Building beginning April 29.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Questions? Contact Assistant Director of Student Relations Audrey LeGrande at &lt;a href="mailto:alegrand@illinois.edu"&gt;alegrand@illinois.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://ece.illinois.edu/brunch"&gt;ece.illinois.edu/brunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Faculty input meeting on regional Big Data Hub</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32712116</link>
            <category>Meeting</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32712116</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The National Science Foundation is launching a 10-year effort to create partnerships around Big Data and the management infrastructure for Big Data. The partnerships and infrastructure are expected to evolve around four regions (South, Northeast, Midwest and West) and NSF is calling for the creation of four Regional Innovation Big Data Hubs. Phase 1 of this effort began with a solicitation (http://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2015/nsf15562/nsf15562.htm) in which NSF expects to fund up to four proposals (one from each region).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Illinois is directing the effort for the Midwest Regional Big Data Innovation Hub with Ed Seidel, Director of NCSA and Klara Nahrstedt, Director of the Coordinated Science Laboratory in the College of Engineering, as leads. Our proposal is being written in collaboration with many organizations across the Midwest covering the broad Big Data challenges of the Midwest, which then academia, industry, foundations, and non-profit organizations can assist to solve. More information will be available as the process unfolds at https://bdhub.info/&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At Illinois, Klara and Ed are seeking knowledge and input for the proposal from researchers who use Big Data in their domains and who would like to see a broad regional and national alliance develop solutions to the challenges of Big Data. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To facilitate researchers' input at Illinois, Klara and Ed are organizing two informational meetings on our campus to inform interested faculty about the possibilities, including ways to contribute and provide input to the proposal and to join the Big Data alliance in Midwest (and nationally). In both meetings, they will present NSF goals for this Big Data initiative and the process Illinois will follow in writing the Midwest Regional Big Data Hub proposal, followed by open discussion. The research areas addressed in these two meetings will not be identical, but rather will cover distinct topics as outlined below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second Big Data Hub Informational Talk is scheduled for 1-3 p.m. Thursday, May 21, in the NCSA Auditorium. Topical discussion will be in the areas of Smart Cities, Advanced Manufacturing, Network Science, Transportation, IT Tools and Services, and Data Science. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope to see you at one of the Informational Talks and to foster broad participation of Illinois faculty in creating Big Data partnerships and infrastructures both across the Midwest and nationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions, please contact Kandace Turner-Jones at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:ktrnrjns@illinois.edu"&gt;ktrnrjns@illinois.edu&lt;/a&gt; or 217-300-2042.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>ECE Building Full Power Outage</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32672388</link>
            <category>Special Event</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32672388</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;div class="message-stanza-depth-1"&gt;From 4 p.m. until midnight May 21, the ECE Building will experience an entire power outage. This is necessary for metering work to be performed. This is considered an excused absence for the remaining hour of the work day and all employees will be compensated for this.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All computers are required to be shut down prior to the power outage. If your lab, research, or specific equipment requires back-up power during this time, please notify Tim Newman, Gary Cromwell, and/or Greg Nelson by no later than Friday, May 8, so proper coordination can occur to ensure nothing is damaged.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>LAUNCH Distinguished Lecture: Lisa Su</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32607650</link>
            <category>Seminar</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2622/32607650</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 08:30:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;ADM President and CEO Lisa Su will give a LAUNCH Distinguished Lecture on Monday, Nov. 9, in the ECE Building's Grainger Auditorium.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A reception will follow in the ECE Building lobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ece.illinois.edu/launch/"&gt;http://www.ece.illinois.edu/launch/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>