<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Slavic, East European &amp; Eurasian Collections - IAS Library</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/2754</link>
        <description>Events related to Slavic studies or library users</description>
        <item>
            <title>Pogo Studio: Capturing the Sounds of the Champaign-Urbana Music</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32123864</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32123864</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Pogo Studio was established in downtown Champaign, IL, in 1985 and quickly earned local, regional and national recognition for its finely crafted recordings and its owner&amp;rsquo;s easy-going nature. &amp;nbsp;The studio remained a fixture of the community&amp;rsquo;s music scene and a valuable resource for regional recording artists for nearly thirty years. &amp;nbsp;During the early 1980s its founder, Mark Rubel, developed his audio engineering and production expertise while working at the University of Illinois&amp;rsquo; Experimental Music Studios and the Faithful Sound recording studio which was located in Urbana, IL. &amp;nbsp;As an active performing bass guitarist, an employee of the talent agency, Blytham Ltd., and project chair for the Champaign County Arts Council, Rubel developed a robust professional relationship with a variety of musicians and bands throughout central Illinois. &amp;nbsp;As a result Pogo Studio recorded and produced over one thousand different projects with such musicians as Adrian Belew and Alison Krauss; rock bands Hum, Menthol, Starcastle and the Vertebrats; &amp;nbsp;community music groups like Amasong; and a variety of performances by student ensembles and faculty from the University of Illinois, Eastern Illinois University and Parkland Community College. &amp;nbsp; This exhibition showcases the unique music legacy of Mark Rubel and Pogo Studio through photographs, oral histories, and sound recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa"&gt;http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Professor Harding and the Illinois Bands During WWI</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32123866</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32123866</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;As war enveloped much of Western Europe in 1914 and 1915 our country struggled to justify its involvement in this conflict and our national leaders overwhelmingly favored peaceful negotiation as the only logical way to end Europe&amp;rsquo;s war. &amp;nbsp;However by 1916 Germany&amp;rsquo;s military had devastated large portions of Belgium and France, and presented a serious threat to Great Britain as well as commercial shipping across the north Atlantic. &amp;nbsp;While fear of a German invasion spawned discussions on the possible need to close the University of Illinois or at least discontinue courses that did not provide relevant training to support a military build-up if needed, the University&amp;rsquo;s band program under the direction of A. Austin Harding continued to provide the campus and the local community with musical artistry, patriotic fervor, and moral support during the darkest days of WWI. &amp;nbsp;This exhibit investigates the challenges that Harding faced as many of his band&amp;rsquo;s members enlisted in the army and navy in 1917 after America entered the war, and highlights the role that Harding and his bands played to support that nation&amp;rsquo;s war effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa"&gt;http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Many Voices: The Great War in America's Songs</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32123867</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32123867</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;When World War I began in 1914 the United States proclaimed that it would follow a policy of strict neutrality &amp;ldquo;in thought and deed,&amp;rdquo; and President Wilson firmly believed that peace was the only course of action needed to resolve the European conflict. &amp;nbsp;Many Americans felt the same way, but as the war&amp;rsquo;s atrocities, both fictional and real, were publicized, some politicians and military leaders began to voice their support for military intervention. &amp;nbsp;After the United States declared war against Germany on April 6, 1917 the country witnessed a dramatic mobilization of industry and financial resources to produce trained soldiers, food, munitions, and equipment which were in short supply at the start of America&amp;rsquo;s involvement. &amp;nbsp;The federal government set up hundreds of temporary agencies with over a million new employees to help redirect the nation&amp;rsquo;s economy. &amp;nbsp;America&amp;rsquo;s sheet music industry joined forces with the U.S. Committee on Public Information to help sell the ideals of patriotism, sacrifice, and volunteerism to the American public as the only way to win this war. &amp;nbsp;This special exhibition from the Smithsonian Institution&amp;rsquo;s National Museum of American History depicts the diverse portrayals of soldiers&amp;rsquo; lives, recruitment of African-American soldiers, women&amp;rsquo;s support for the war effort, and the country&amp;rsquo;s financial and personal sacrifice through the melodies, lyrics and graphic illustrations of sheet music that were produced between 1917 and 1919.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa"&gt;http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Audubon Plate of the Week: Ferruginous Thrush</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32422241</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32422241</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Therapy Dogs at Undergraduate Library</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32704141</link>
            <category>Special Events</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32704141</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Does Finals Week stress you or your patrons out? Looking for a sympathetic ear and sage advice &amp;ndash; or perhaps a cold nose and a confident wag? &amp;nbsp;Then you should roll over to one of the Library&amp;rsquo;s Therapy Dog events. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Audubon Plate of the Week: Wood Pewee</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32422242</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32422242</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Main Library Open House</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32703972</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32703972</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Main Library first floor corridor is open on Commencement Weekend from 1pm - 4pm so students and parents can view the Bronze Tablets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Main Library Open House</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32703973</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32703973</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Main Library first floor corridor is open on Commencement Weekend from 1pm - 4pm so students and parents can view the Bronze Tablets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707105</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707105</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707110</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707110</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2015 Ralph and Ruth Fisher Forum: Violence in Twenthieth-Century Russia and Eurasia: Experience, Affect, Memory, and Legacies</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32370575</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32370575</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;VIOLENCE IN TWENTIETH-CENTURY RUSSIA AND EURASIA: EXPERIENCE, AFFECT, MEMORY, AND LEGACIES&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;June 19-20, 2015&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian, East European, and Eurasian Center&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organized by Harriet Murav and Mark Steinberg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a poem dedicated to the memory of 19 June 1914, Anna Akhmatova wrote &amp;quot;we aged a hundred years and this / Happened in a single hour.&amp;quot; The twentieth century brought unprecedented violence to the European world, not least in the Russian Empire and the Soviet Union. The years 1914-1921, among the most bloody and destructive in Russia's history, cannot be understood in isolation from the whole jagged landscape of violence - international wars, violent political force, national and revolutionary violence, ethnic and racial violence, interpersonal and domestic violence. Boundaries do not easily stand in violent conditions. Emancipatory and repressive violence mix and blur. Purposeful political and social struggles mix with &amp;quot;hooliganism&amp;quot; and commonplace human brutality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And violence itself is only part of the story. The twentieth century, especially its first decades, saw a remarkable explosion of creativity in the arts, literature, science, politics, philosophy, and social organization, as well as extraordinary technological innovation and invention. Indeed, violence itself could be understood in radically different ways, including as creativity, even as actions in the name of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2015 Fisher Forum will examine the immediacy, effects, and refractions of violence in Russia and Eurasia (defined as the spaces occupied by the Russian Empire and the Soviet Union) from perspective across disciplines. Papers will also engage the question of how to interpret and theorize violence, as practice, as experience, as legacy. Indeed, while our focus is on the past, we cannot ignore lasting effects and persistent meanings, including for our own time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LIST OF PARTICIPANTS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please also see: http://www.reeec.illinois.edu/events/conferences/2015FisherForum.html&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707111</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707111</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707113</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707113</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707117</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707117</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707128</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32707128</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Familiar Strangers: The Georgian Diaspora and the Evolution of Soviet Empire</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32706929</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2754/32706929</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the history of Georgians beyond the Georgian republic from 1917 to the present, this presentation explores the rise and fall of the Soviet multiethnic empire from the perspective of its most prominent internal diaspora. Joseph Stalin (Jughashvili) was just one of a group of Georgian revolutionaries who came to power in the early years of Soviet rule and directed the development of the new state. After the socialist state was established, Soviet citizens sought new opportunities for leisure and consumption and found them at the Georgian restaurant, where they adopted the distinctive rituals of the Georgian table. During Khrushchev&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Thaw,&amp;rdquo; Georgian cultural entrepreneurs embodied the era&amp;rsquo;s spirit of spontaneity as popular ethnic entertainers specializing in song, dance, and theater. As official life grew stagnant under Brezhnev, Georgians thrived in the burgeoning informal economy. Finally, with the advent of Gorbachev&amp;rsquo;s reforms, it was a Georgian film, &lt;em&gt;Repentance&lt;/em&gt;, that explored the furthest limits of allowable expression, calling into question the very legitimacy of Soviet power. The prominence of the Georgian diaspora suggests that the Soviet Union was not simply a Russian empire, nor merely a multiethnic state composed of separate nations; instead, it was an empire of diasporas, where politics, culture, and economics were constituted by the mixing of a diverse array of mobile nationalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik R. Scott&lt;/strong&gt; is Assistant Professor of Russian and Soviet history at the University of Kansas. Drawing on years of fieldwork and knowledge of several regional languages, his research and teaching explore migration and diaspora within and beyond the imperial borders of Russia and Eurasia. His book, &lt;em&gt;Familiar Strangers: The Georgian Diaspora and the Multiethnic Soviet Empire &lt;/em&gt;(forthcoming from Oxford University Press in 2016), reimagines the Soviet empire by revealing how external borders concealed an array of specialized internal diaspora populations. He has recently begun a new project on Soviet defectors and the production of Cold War borders, focusing in particular on the winding journeys of defectors through border zones, transit hubs, extraterritorial spaces, and contested areas beyond the limits of state jurisdiction. He teaches undergraduate and graduate courses on Russian and Soviet history, the Cold War, comparative empires, and migration in global perspective. He received his Ph.D. from the University of California, Berkeley in 2011 and was the Post-Doctoral Fellow in Caucasian and Central Asian Affairs at Georgetown University&amp;rsquo;s Center for Eurasian, Russian, and East European Studies from 2011 to 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>