<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>College of Engineering, Engineering Update</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/2768</link>
        <description>This moderated calendar contains a listing of student events submitted by users.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Book signing with Walt Robb</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2768/32703971</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2768/32703971</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Walt Robb earned his PhD in chemical engineering from the University of Illinois in 1951 (in three years) and joined GE as a young researcher. As the CT scanning revolution got underway and MRI technology took off, Robb oversaw the business expand from a break-even, $100 million business to a highly profitable and growing enterprise. In 1993, President Bill Clinton presented him with a National Medal of Technology and Innovation for his foresight and leadership in the MRI and CT imaging industry. He is a recipient of the university's Alumni Achievement Award and the President&amp;rsquo;s Medallion. Robb will be at Roger Adams Laboratory May 14 for a book signing and reception. His new book, &amp;ldquo;Taking Risks: Getting Ahead in Business and Life,&amp;rdquo; offers advice for students and new graduates, technology start-ups, and managers at all levels. He also shares insights on his 20 years of working under fellow UI graduate and GE&amp;rsquo;s longtime CEO Jack Welch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>nano@illinois Research Experience for Undergraduates (REU)</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2768/32414427</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2768/32414427</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The nano@illinois REU is a National Science Foundation (NSF) funded Research Experience for Undergraduates Site in the area of nanotechnology at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign from 2014-2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>