<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>College of Education Public Events (MASTER)</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/2771</link>
        <description>All public events from the College of Education and affiliated groups.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Yew-Chung – Bernard Spodek Scholar Ceremony</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32712843</link>
            <category>College of Education</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32712843</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join the College of Education at the ceremony honoring Dr. Stephanie Sanders-Smith, Assistant Professor of Curriculum &amp;amp; Instruction, as the inaugural Yew Chung &amp;ndash; Bernard Spodek Scholar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Geojam - Family Math Night!</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32691164</link>
            <category>College of Education</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32691164</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 17:45:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;GeoJam is a free community math event hosted by University students preparing to be mathematics teachers. Interact with these University students as you and your kids complete building challenges, life-size puzzles, reasoning challenges, number games, computer simulations, geometric coloring, and lots of other math and logic related activities suitable for all ages. Everyone who comes gets a free raffle ticket and at the end of the night, dozens and dozens of great prizes donated by local businesses will be raffled off.&amp;nbsp; Enjoy the math activities any time from 5:45 - 7:30, then free snacks are served from 7:30 - 7:45, then the raffle and awards ceremony is from 7:45 - 8:00.&amp;nbsp; So come!... and have a fun, positive, and educational family math experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>College of Education Online Graduation Reception</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32688430</link>
            <category>College of Education</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32688430</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 17:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us in celebrating the achievements of all of our online graduates!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refreshement will be served. Family &amp;amp; friends are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP to &lt;a href="mailto:jrooseve@illinois.edu "&gt;jrooseve@illinois.edu &lt;/a&gt;by Thursday, May 7, 2015&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>College of Education Convocation</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32294789</link>
            <category>College of Education</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32294789</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 17:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The College of Education 2015 Convocation will be held on Saturday, May 16 from 5 &amp;ndash; 6:30 p.m. in the Foellinger Great Hall at the Krannert Center for Performing Arts. &amp;nbsp;More information will be sent out in the spring about the ceremony, tickets, deadlines, and reception, and the website will be updated in January. &amp;nbsp;We hope this early alert will facilitate planning for you and your families.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Practical Wisdom in Social Inquiry Practice: A Symposium in Honor of Professor Thomas A. Schwandt</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32720257</link>
            <category>College of Education</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32720257</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Professor Thomas Schwandt has devoted his career to encouraging evaluators and other social inquirers to think critically about their professional practice, to engage meaningfully with ideas from multiple domains of human endeavor, and to anchor professional actions in ethical and moral reasoning. Professor Schwandt&amp;rsquo;s voice has been a highly distinctive one amidst a loud chorus dominated by methodological issues and technical debates. This symposium will honor Professor Schwandt&amp;rsquo;s irreplaceable contributions to social inquiry across many fields and will celebrate his legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symposium will feature presentations by invited colleagues, students, and friends of Tom&amp;rsquo;s, from all around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>University Primary School Summer Camps June &amp; July 2015</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32672557</link>
            <category>University Primary School</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32672557</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 08:45:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;div class="page" title="Page 1"&gt;
&lt;div class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;div class="column"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University Primary School Summer Camp is a weekly camp June 8-July 31 Monday- Friday, 8:45 a.m.-1:00 p.m and/or 1:00 p.m.-5:15 p.m. for children ages 3-12 years old. Campers need not attend University Primary School during the regular school year to attend summer camp. Campers may sign up for single or multiple weeks. Camp experiences for the 3-7 year old group will primarily occur in the school yard gardens and playground where campers will spend time working with plants, water, and new friends. Camp experiences for the 7-12 year old group will include art projects and exploration in sciences. Both groups will have indoor time each day to &amp;ldquo;cool off&amp;rdquo; with inside activities including literacy time. &amp;nbsp;More information:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://education.illinois.edu/ups/documents/2015SummerCampBrochure_JuneandJuly.pdf"&gt;http://education.illinois.edu/ups/documents/2015SummerCampBrochure_JuneandJuly.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>University of Illinois Writing Project Young Writers Camps</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32682897</link>
            <category>College of Education</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2771/32682897</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Students come to the camp to experience being in a community of writers.&amp;nbsp; Our teachers guide that community and teach students skills to expand their writing&amp;nbsp;abilities.&amp;nbsp; The students work in small groups, as well as getting some focused&amp;nbsp;attention from teachers.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Students will be free to create unique original pieces of writing in this communal environment. &amp;nbsp;Students will make friends, learn to work collaboratively with others, and have great fun writing.&amp;nbsp; We strive to provide students with an enjoyable experience that will leave them with a positive attitude about their ability to write. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Week 1: &amp;nbsp;July 27 to July 31, 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Week 2: &amp;nbsp;August 2 to August 7, 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;For more information and registration information, go to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://education.illinois.edu/uiwp/young-writers-camps"&gt;http://education.illinois.edu/uiwp/young-writers-camps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>