<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Information Technology Accessibility Initiative (ITaccess)</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/2951</link>
        <description>Events and training sponsored or announced by the Information Technology Accessibility Initiative (ITaccess)</description>
        <item>
            <title>Accessible JavaScript Library Testing Group</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541681</link>
            <category>IT Accessibility</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541681</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Discussion for JS Library Accessibility Testing. Libraries include JQUERY-UI, Bootstrap.JS, and custom built widgets and components. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Goals include:&lt;br /&gt;Identification of library widgets&lt;br /&gt;Testing for accessibility&lt;br /&gt;Discussion of how widgets should function to meet accessibility&lt;br /&gt;Reporting of bugs and desired features to meet accessibility criteria&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A testing group is currently meeting weekly to work on these things. For more information on how you can join the working group in person or by teleconference, contact Christy Blew at clblew@illinois.edu&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Accessible JavaScript Library Testing Group</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541682</link>
            <category>IT Accessibility</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541682</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Discussion for JS Library Accessibility Testing. Libraries include JQUERY-UI, Bootstrap.JS, and custom built widgets and components. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Goals include:&lt;br /&gt;Identification of library widgets&lt;br /&gt;Testing for accessibility&lt;br /&gt;Discussion of how widgets should function to meet accessibility&lt;br /&gt;Reporting of bugs and desired features to meet accessibility criteria&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A testing group is currently meeting weekly to work on these things. For more information on how you can join the working group in person or by teleconference, contact Christy Blew at clblew@illinois.edu&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Digital and Technology Access: the Role of Law I the Limits of Law</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541687</link>
            <category>IT Accessibility</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541687</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This session will explore the role of the law in advancing digital accessibility in the United States. The ADA doesn't mention websites or the Internet. Does it matter? Court decisions, voluntary settlements, advocacy by the Department of Justice and Department of Education and new regulations are making the digital environment more accessible. But is it enough? Participants in this webinar will learn about recent litigation, Structured Negotiations, and administrative actions making websites, mobile applications and other technology available to people with disabilities. We'll talk about how the ADA and other state and federal laws can advance digital inclusion and the various strategies that advocates have at their disposal to effectively use those laws. We'll look at the law's role in expanding digital access in education, finance, healthcare, retail and more. Can effective use of the law help close the digital divide? What do you think? There will be plenty of time for questions and answers. Participants will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What laws (in the U.S.) require digital accessibility and how are they being Implemented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the U.S. Department of Justice have to say about digital accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the law protect the privacy of financial and health information for people with disabilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Accessible JavaScript Library Testing Group</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541683</link>
            <category>IT Accessibility</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541683</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 15:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Discussion for JS Library Accessibility Testing. Libraries include JQUERY-UI, Bootstrap.JS, and custom built widgets and components. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Goals include:&lt;br /&gt;Identification of library widgets&lt;br /&gt;Testing for accessibility&lt;br /&gt;Discussion of how widgets should function to meet accessibility&lt;br /&gt;Reporting of bugs and desired features to meet accessibility criteria&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A testing group is currently meeting weekly to work on these things. For more information on how you can join the working group in person or by teleconference, contact Christy Blew at clblew@illinois.edu&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Turning Text Into Speech: Real World Applications and Examples</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541689</link>
            <category>IT Accessibility</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/2951/32541689</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Computers these days have a lot to say but only if you know the right way to ask them. With text-to-speech a user can have the computer read almost any text out loud. This can be a life changing tool for people who are blind, low vision, or have a print related disability. But what are these tools, how do they work, and what does it look like in real life for an everyday user? In this Webinar we will explore text-to-speech tools available on computers, tablets, and smart phones through the use of real world examples. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; As a trainer of blind and low vision computer users Jonathan has gained a significant amount of hands-on experience of text-to-speech technology and will demonstrate the way his clients find success with text-to-speech tools. You&amp;rsquo;ll also learn how people with print related disables like dyslexia can leverage these tools to find success. Demonstrations will include: &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screen readers like JAWS for Windows and VoiceOver for Apple devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text-to-Speech and magnification software like ZoomText and MAGic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in reading tools on the iPad and iPhone like Speak Selection and Speak Screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optical Character Recognition (OCR) software like the KNFB Reader and ABBYY FineReader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight and read tools like NaturalReader and Snap&amp;amp;Read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrations will include both paid and free software options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>