<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>National Resource Centers</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/3058</link>
        <description>Events for National Resource Centers at UIUC</description>
        <item>
            <title>Public talk:  “Ebola in Sierra Leone: A Behavioral Spillover.”</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32701635</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32701635</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Aiah Lebbie, Head of the Department of Biological Sciences at Njala University, will be giving a public talk, titled &amp;ldquo;Ebola in Sierra Leone: A Behavioral Spillover.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Illinois-Njala Global Health Symposium</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32701803</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32701803</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The keynote speaker is&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Aiah Lebbie&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Njala University in Sierra Leone where he is the head of the Department of Biological Sciences. Dr. Debbie earned his BSc from the University of Sierra Leone in 1989, and his MS in Conservation Biology &amp;amp; Sustainable Development (1995) and PhD in Forest Ecology &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;Management (2001) from the University of Wisconsin-Madison. His research focuses on integrating biological knowledge in addressing conservation/biodiversity issues in Liberia and Sierra Leone with an emphasis on human interactions with tropical ecosystems and understanding social&amp;nbsp;consequences. His research encompasses sacred groves (cultural &amp;amp; biological), ecology of tropical plants and understanding the context in which&amp;nbsp;health, disease, traditional knowledge and medicinal plants converge. He&amp;nbsp;has&amp;nbsp;taught and researched for Njala University College, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Njala University, and the Environment Foundation for Africa.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The symposium will have opening remarks by Dr. Reitumetse Obakeng Mabokela, who is the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign Vice Provost for International Affairs &amp;amp; Global Strategy. In addition, there will be a history of the Illinois-Njala Global Health Partnership, the introduction of the Illinois-Njala Global Health Certificate, and roundtable discussions. Dinner will be provided.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>"Development from the Inside Out"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32703466</link>
            <category>campus-wide lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32703466</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Molly Melching will discuss a recent visit to Eastern Senegal, where she found the community members, particularly women and youth, totally engaged in promoting human rights, as well as women and youth leadership.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Health in Africa and the Post-2015 Millennium Development Goals</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32393596</link>
            <category>symposium</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32393596</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707105</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707105</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707110</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707110</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2015 Ralph and Ruth Fisher Forum: Violence in Twenthieth-Century Russia and Eurasia: Experience, Affect, Memory, and Legacies</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32370575</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32370575</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;VIOLENCE IN TWENTIETH-CENTURY RUSSIA AND EURASIA: EXPERIENCE, AFFECT, MEMORY, AND LEGACIES&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;June 19-20, 2015&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian, East European, and Eurasian Center&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organized by Harriet Murav and Mark Steinberg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a poem dedicated to the memory of 19 June 1914, Anna Akhmatova wrote &amp;quot;we aged a hundred years and this / Happened in a single hour.&amp;quot; The twentieth century brought unprecedented violence to the European world, not least in the Russian Empire and the Soviet Union. The years 1914-1921, among the most bloody and destructive in Russia's history, cannot be understood in isolation from the whole jagged landscape of violence - international wars, violent political force, national and revolutionary violence, ethnic and racial violence, interpersonal and domestic violence. Boundaries do not easily stand in violent conditions. Emancipatory and repressive violence mix and blur. Purposeful political and social struggles mix with &amp;quot;hooliganism&amp;quot; and commonplace human brutality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And violence itself is only part of the story. The twentieth century, especially its first decades, saw a remarkable explosion of creativity in the arts, literature, science, politics, philosophy, and social organization, as well as extraordinary technological innovation and invention. Indeed, violence itself could be understood in radically different ways, including as creativity, even as actions in the name of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2015 Fisher Forum will examine the immediacy, effects, and refractions of violence in Russia and Eurasia (defined as the spaces occupied by the Russian Empire and the Soviet Union) from perspective across disciplines. Papers will also engage the question of how to interpret and theorize violence, as practice, as experience, as legacy. Indeed, while our focus is on the past, we cannot ignore lasting effects and persistent meanings, including for our own time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LIST OF PARTICIPANTS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please also see: http://www.reeec.illinois.edu/events/conferences/2015FisherForum.html&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707111</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707111</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707113</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707113</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707117</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707117</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707128</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32707128</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hispanic Linguistics Symposium</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32633823</link>
            <category>Symposium</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32633823</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Spanish and Portuguese will host the Hispanic Linguistics Symposium from September 24 &amp;ndash; 27, 2015. HLS is an annual conference with a focus on theoretical and applied linguistics in Spanish and Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Familiar Strangers: The Georgian Diaspora and the Evolution of Soviet Empire</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32706929</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32706929</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the history of Georgians beyond the Georgian republic from 1917 to the present, this presentation explores the rise and fall of the Soviet multiethnic empire from the perspective of its most prominent internal diaspora. Joseph Stalin (Jughashvili) was just one of a group of Georgian revolutionaries who came to power in the early years of Soviet rule and directed the development of the new state. After the socialist state was established, Soviet citizens sought new opportunities for leisure and consumption and found them at the Georgian restaurant, where they adopted the distinctive rituals of the Georgian table. During Khrushchev&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Thaw,&amp;rdquo; Georgian cultural entrepreneurs embodied the era&amp;rsquo;s spirit of spontaneity as popular ethnic entertainers specializing in song, dance, and theater. As official life grew stagnant under Brezhnev, Georgians thrived in the burgeoning informal economy. Finally, with the advent of Gorbachev&amp;rsquo;s reforms, it was a Georgian film, &lt;em&gt;Repentance&lt;/em&gt;, that explored the furthest limits of allowable expression, calling into question the very legitimacy of Soviet power. The prominence of the Georgian diaspora suggests that the Soviet Union was not simply a Russian empire, nor merely a multiethnic state composed of separate nations; instead, it was an empire of diasporas, where politics, culture, and economics were constituted by the mixing of a diverse array of mobile nationalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik R. Scott&lt;/strong&gt; is Assistant Professor of Russian and Soviet history at the University of Kansas. Drawing on years of fieldwork and knowledge of several regional languages, his research and teaching explore migration and diaspora within and beyond the imperial borders of Russia and Eurasia. His book, &lt;em&gt;Familiar Strangers: The Georgian Diaspora and the Multiethnic Soviet Empire &lt;/em&gt;(forthcoming from Oxford University Press in 2016), reimagines the Soviet empire by revealing how external borders concealed an array of specialized internal diaspora populations. He has recently begun a new project on Soviet defectors and the production of Cold War borders, focusing in particular on the winding journeys of defectors through border zones, transit hubs, extraterritorial spaces, and contested areas beyond the limits of state jurisdiction. He teaches undergraduate and graduate courses on Russian and Soviet history, the Cold War, comparative empires, and migration in global perspective. He received his Ph.D. from the University of California, Berkeley in 2011 and was the Post-Doctoral Fellow in Caucasian and Central Asian Affairs at Georgetown University&amp;rsquo;s Center for Eurasian, Russian, and East European Studies from 2011 to 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>"The Ganga, National River of India: Its Heritage and Future"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/26307197</link>
            <category>Symposium</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/26307197</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The symposium will bring together scholars from many diverse disciplines who will speak to the multi-faceted heritage of the Ganga, discuss how this precious heritage is at risk, and develop an integrated framework guiding ecologically and culturally sustainable approaches to conservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics to be covered include Ganga&amp;rsquo;s purity and pollution, mapping urbanization and festivals, arts of the Ganga, and the sacred Landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lecture: Cosmopolitan Language Systems in the Mediterranean</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32574279</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3058/32574279</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 17:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karla Mallette studies communications between literary traditions in the medieval Mediterranean&amp;mdash;especially Arabic and the Romance vernaculars&amp;mdash;and the way that we remember that history today. Her first book, &lt;em&gt;The Kingdom of Sicily, 1100-1250: A Literary History&lt;/em&gt; (University of Pennsylvania Press, 2005), traced the transition between Arabic and Italian literary traditions in medieval Sicily; her second, &lt;em&gt;European Modernity and the Arab Mediterranean&lt;/em&gt; (University of Pennsylvania Press, 2010), focused on a southern European tradition of scholarship that identifies the origins of modernity in the contact between Islamic and Christian civilizations in the medieval Mediterranean. Her current project, tentatively titled&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Lives of the Great Languages: Cosmopolitan Languages in the Medieval Mediterranean&lt;/em&gt;, studies the strategies that language uses to transcend the boundaries that language creates. By profiling two pre-modern cosmopolitan languages, Arabic and Latin, and acknowledging the emergent cosmopolitan languages of the twenty-first century, the book contextualizes and defamiliarizes the national language system of European modernity. She has published essays on medieval translations of Aristotelian philosophy, framed narratives, European Orientalism, and Mediterranean Studies, in addition to Italian literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>