<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Family Resiliency Center</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/3324</link>
        <description>Calendar for FRC</description>
        <item>
            <title>ABC (Autism, Behavior, and Complex Medical Needs) South Conference</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3324/32553072</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3324/32553072</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The ABC conferences emphasize evidence-based and concrete strategies to address the struggles providers encounter related to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;utism,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;ehavioral Challenges and&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;omplex Medical Needs (ABC). 2015 marks the first year that an ABC South conference will be held to serve the professional development and support of child-serving professionals in the greater Southern and Central Illinois Regions. In addition to a new location, this will be the first ABC conference to adopt a trauma-informed &amp;lsquo;lens&amp;rsquo;, and focus on the pervasive effects of trauma as they relate to all disciplines serving children and their families, especially children with special needs. Trauma is a widespread public health issue whose implications are not limited to the behavioral health sector. Therefore, this conference emphasizes a multidisciplinary, interprofessional approach to most effectively serve people who have experienced trauma. We invite you and your colleagues to join pediatricians, family physicians, healthcare professionals and community service providers, including home visitors, child care providers, Early Intervention professionals, social workers, and family case management, for a day of excellent educational content and networking with colleagues throughout the state. Throughout the day, three educational tracks (A, B, and C) will run concurrently in important breakout sessions. In addition ICAAP is pleased to announce that participants will gain valuable insights from three keynote speakers, as well as important resources from a variety of exhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Food and Family Conference</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3324/32552358</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3324/32552358</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>CEHN at Illinois Symposium</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3324/32550667</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3324/32550667</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>