<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Center of Health, Aging, and Disability Calendar</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/3328</link>
        <description>Center of Health, Aging, and Disability Calendar</description>
        <item>
            <title>William T. Grant Scholars Program: Campus Limited Submission</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3328/32495196</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3328/32495196</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The William T. Grant Scholars Program is for early-career researchers in the social, behavioral, and health sciences. We encourage Scholars to tackle important questions that will advance theory, policy, and practice for youth. Applicants identify new methods, disciplines, or content they want to learn, and propose five-year research plans that foster their growth in those areas. We recognize that early-career researchers are rarely given incentives or support to take such risks, so this award includes a mentoring component. Potential Scholars should have a promising track record of conducting high-quality research, but want to pursue a significant shift in their trajectories as researchers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>EHR Core Research</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3328/32278068</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3328/32278068</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The fundamental research that ECR supports advances the frontiers of understanding about how more people learn, and use more STEM knowledge, more effectively. To do this, ECR projects are grounded in theory, ask well formulated research questions, employ relevant data and analytic techniques, and contribute to the growing body of literature on STEM education research. ECR projects bring together the expertise, literatures, methods and learning priorities of the entire range of scientific communities represented by the NSF research directorates as well as EHR. ECR supports researchers who use large scale, next generation data resources and relevant big data analytic techniques to advance fundamental research in STEM learning, STEM learning environments, STEM workforce development, and broadening participation research where appropriate. ECR also supports research on efforts to make that knowledge available to other researchers, education developers, leaders and practitioners so that research is used broadly to improve STEM education and the development of a flexible, knowledgeable and diverse STEM workforce. The specific strands of research ECR seeks to support include STEM learning and learning environments, workforce development, and broadening participation in STEM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>