<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>DURP events</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/3591</link>
        <description>DURP events</description>
        <item>
            <title>UP478 Final Presentation, Welcoming Immigrant Owned Businesses in Urbana</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32613157</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32613157</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>DURP Convocation</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/31976871</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/31976871</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>DURP Faculty Retreat</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32523217</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32523217</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 12:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>International Sociological Association RC-43: Housing and the Built Environment Conference</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32465124</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32465124</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This conference is hosted by the Housing and Built Environment Research Committee of the International Sociological Association (RC43).&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Theme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing economic inequality and socio-spatial polarization challenge both developed and developing countries. Housing policy stands at a crossroads--will our housing systems widen or close the gap between those with means and those without? Will residential neighborhoods serve as social and economic melting pots, or will they harden the boundaries reflective of the growing wealth and power of elite social groups? What should be done and what can be done are very different questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can housing markets and policies better serve as one of the important factors promoting social outcomes in which all have fairer access to the opportunities and benefits that cities and neighborhoods provide?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Call &amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; The RC43 encourages cross-disciplinary debate and welcomes housing research papers from all social science disciplines. We invite both panel session proposals and individual abstracts related to the following themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Housing markets, structural crises, and socio-spatial outcomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The role of housing policy in socio-spatial inequality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparative contexts: housing system diversity and/or convergence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Housing and social theory in a globalized, neoliberal era&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/public housing strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The changing role of the private rented sector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neighborhood socio-spatial change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Housing through the lifecourse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papers should be 5,000 to 8,000 words inclusive. Sessions are two hours long, and can have up to five papers. Individual presentations should be 15 minutes long.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; The deadline for abstracts is March 15, 2015. Abstracts should be submitted via email to &lt;a href="mailto:isa.rc43@gmail.com"&gt;isa.rc43@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a pre-conference for PhD students on September 16, 2015. More information on this day will be coming soon; please check the website for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Housing in an Unequal World conference is organized by the RC43 in collaboration with the University of Illinois-Chicago, and the University of Illinois-Urbana-Champaign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Illinois APA Conference</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32400511</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/3591/32400511</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>