<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Geography and Geographic Information Science (GGIS)</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/4024</link>
        <description>GGIS Events Calendar</description>
        <item>
            <title>The Israel-Palestine E-waste Commodity Chain: Findings and Reflections</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4024/32718926</link>
            <category>Speaker</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4024/32718926</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last several years, Yaakov Garb has worked with a small team to explore and document the informal Palestinian-Israeli entrepreneurial commodity chain through which most Israeli electronic waste has been informally transferred to a cluster of Palestinian villages and dismantled, with valuable materials (primarily copper and motherboards) shipped via Israel to destinations abroad, and the remainder crudely burned and dumped in the rural landscape. Drawing on over a hundred interviews with stakeholders in this commodity chain, extensive field observation, as well as remote sensing imagery and traffic counts, the&amp;nbsp;team has constructed a portrait of this value chain (actors, prices, volumes, and dynamics) and documented its severe environmental and human health consequences. They have&amp;nbsp;also worked with the local Palestinian community to develop a business model, transition strategy, and bargaining power vis-&amp;agrave;-vis the Israeli system to enable allow a shift to cleaner operation while preserving livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This&amp;nbsp;talk will describe this e-waste commodity chain, its geopolitical contexts, and the results of our research and advocacy efforts. It will reflect&amp;nbsp;on the broader implications of this case study for thinking about informal commodity chains, their ability to move materials and rework landscapes at large scales, and what we know about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yaakov Garb&lt;/strong&gt; is Lecturer at Ben Gurion University and an Adjunct Assistant Professor of International Studies at the Watson Institute, Brown University. He draws on a training in environmental studies and in science and technology studies (STS) in research, teaching, and consulting on environmental and urban issues. Dr. Garb specializes in projects demanding interdisciplinary perspectives, a combination of qualitative and quantitative methodologies, and a merging of analysis with advocacy for change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Michael Watts on Spaces of Insurgency</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4024/32686085</link>
            <category>Speaker</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4024/32686085</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 15:00:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk will examine the rise of two insurgencies in contemporary Nigeria, on their face of very different character. One - Boko Haram - is a neo-Salafist Islamist movement associated with the northern savanna and draped in the language of Calpihal restoration and True Islam; the other - the Movement for the Emancipation of the Niger Delta (MEND) - a secular movement arising on the oilfields and in the creeks of of the forested Niger delta speaking the language of self determination, resource control and constitutional reform. Drawing upon the ideas of Henri Lefebvre among others, this talk shall&amp;nbsp;attempt to argue for their 'family resemblances' rooted in the relations between petro-capitalism, spatial fragmentation and the exclusion of youth from multiple forms of authority. Each must be grounded too in regionally and culturally specific forms of&amp;nbsp; state-building, warfare and local history which gives to each insurgency a specific coloration and inflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professor Michael J. Watts&lt;/strong&gt; is Professor of Geography and Development Studies and Chair of the Department of Geography at University of California, Berkeley, where he has taught since 1979. Professor Watts is a leading figure in human geography, particularly political ecology. Although strongly identified with a Marxist tradition and with political economy, his work since the 1970s has extended from the human ecology of agrarian societies in Africa to the theorization of culture and difference, and the reasons behind the prosecution of war under contemporary capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>