<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Library Calendar</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/4092</link>
        <description>all library events</description>
        <item>
            <title>Pogo Studio: Capturing the Sounds of the Champaign-Urbana Music</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32123864</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32123864</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Pogo Studio was established in downtown Champaign, IL, in 1985 and quickly earned local, regional and national recognition for its finely crafted recordings and its owner&amp;rsquo;s easy-going nature. &amp;nbsp;The studio remained a fixture of the community&amp;rsquo;s music scene and a valuable resource for regional recording artists for nearly thirty years. &amp;nbsp;During the early 1980s its founder, Mark Rubel, developed his audio engineering and production expertise while working at the University of Illinois&amp;rsquo; Experimental Music Studios and the Faithful Sound recording studio which was located in Urbana, IL. &amp;nbsp;As an active performing bass guitarist, an employee of the talent agency, Blytham Ltd., and project chair for the Champaign County Arts Council, Rubel developed a robust professional relationship with a variety of musicians and bands throughout central Illinois. &amp;nbsp;As a result Pogo Studio recorded and produced over one thousand different projects with such musicians as Adrian Belew and Alison Krauss; rock bands Hum, Menthol, Starcastle and the Vertebrats; &amp;nbsp;community music groups like Amasong; and a variety of performances by student ensembles and faculty from the University of Illinois, Eastern Illinois University and Parkland Community College. &amp;nbsp; This exhibition showcases the unique music legacy of Mark Rubel and Pogo Studio through photographs, oral histories, and sound recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa"&gt;http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Professor Harding and the Illinois Bands During WWI</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32123866</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32123866</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;As war enveloped much of Western Europe in 1914 and 1915 our country struggled to justify its involvement in this conflict and our national leaders overwhelmingly favored peaceful negotiation as the only logical way to end Europe&amp;rsquo;s war. &amp;nbsp;However by 1916 Germany&amp;rsquo;s military had devastated large portions of Belgium and France, and presented a serious threat to Great Britain as well as commercial shipping across the north Atlantic. &amp;nbsp;While fear of a German invasion spawned discussions on the possible need to close the University of Illinois or at least discontinue courses that did not provide relevant training to support a military build-up if needed, the University&amp;rsquo;s band program under the direction of A. Austin Harding continued to provide the campus and the local community with musical artistry, patriotic fervor, and moral support during the darkest days of WWI. &amp;nbsp;This exhibit investigates the challenges that Harding faced as many of his band&amp;rsquo;s members enlisted in the army and navy in 1917 after America entered the war, and highlights the role that Harding and his bands played to support that nation&amp;rsquo;s war effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa"&gt;http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Many Voices: The Great War in America's Songs</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32123867</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32123867</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;When World War I began in 1914 the United States proclaimed that it would follow a policy of strict neutrality &amp;ldquo;in thought and deed,&amp;rdquo; and President Wilson firmly believed that peace was the only course of action needed to resolve the European conflict. &amp;nbsp;Many Americans felt the same way, but as the war&amp;rsquo;s atrocities, both fictional and real, were publicized, some politicians and military leaders began to voice their support for military intervention. &amp;nbsp;After the United States declared war against Germany on April 6, 1917 the country witnessed a dramatic mobilization of industry and financial resources to produce trained soldiers, food, munitions, and equipment which were in short supply at the start of America&amp;rsquo;s involvement. &amp;nbsp;The federal government set up hundreds of temporary agencies with over a million new employees to help redirect the nation&amp;rsquo;s economy. &amp;nbsp;America&amp;rsquo;s sheet music industry joined forces with the U.S. Committee on Public Information to help sell the ideals of patriotism, sacrifice, and volunteerism to the American public as the only way to win this war. &amp;nbsp;This special exhibition from the Smithsonian Institution&amp;rsquo;s National Museum of American History depicts the diverse portrayals of soldiers&amp;rsquo; lives, recruitment of African-American soldiers, women&amp;rsquo;s support for the war effort, and the country&amp;rsquo;s financial and personal sacrifice through the melodies, lyrics and graphic illustrations of sheet music that were produced between 1917 and 1919.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa"&gt;http://archives.library.illinois.edu/sousa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Audubon Plate of the Week: Ferruginous Thrush</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32422241</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32422241</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Therapy Dogs at Undergraduate Library</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32704141</link>
            <category>Special Events</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32704141</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Does Finals Week stress you or your patrons out? Looking for a sympathetic ear and sage advice &amp;ndash; or perhaps a cold nose and a confident wag? &amp;nbsp;Then you should roll over to one of the Library&amp;rsquo;s Therapy Dog events. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Audubon Plate of the Week: Wood Pewee</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32422242</link>
            <category>Exhibit</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32422242</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Samuel Johnson and the Hookers' Best Friend</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32262227</link>
            <category>exhibition</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32262227</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float: left; margin-right: 30px; margin-left: 25px;" src="http://illinois.edu/cms/2068/b_d639v_1777b_doddgenuine_p1_0001_copy.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="385" /&gt;For the last meeting of the 2014-15 &lt;em&gt;No. 44 Society&lt;/em&gt; season, we welcome Paul T. Ruxin, who will talk about Samuel Johnson and the Revd. William Dodd, supporter of Magdalen Hospital for the Reception of Penitent Prostitutes, founded in 1758.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 25 years Mr. Ruxin served as chairman of the international legal firm Jones Day's specialized energy industry practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was regularly listed in &lt;em&gt;The Best Lawyers in America&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and in &lt;em&gt;Chambers USA: &amp;nbsp;America's Leading Business Lawyers &lt;/em&gt;during his 41-year legal career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruxin is a member of the Rowfant Club of Cleveland, The Caxton Club of Chicago, The Grolier Club of New York, and The Club of Odd Volumes of Boston. He is Past Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Folger Shakespeare Library of Washington, D.C. and is a member of the Board of Trustees of The Newberry Library of Chicago, the Board of Directors of The Poetry Foundation a Governor of Dr. Johnson's House Trust (London) and a member of the Founders' Council of The American Writers' Museum. He is also a member of The Association Internationale de Bibliophilie, The Editorial Committee of the &lt;em&gt;Yale Editions of the Private Papers of James Boswell&lt;/em&gt;, the Visiting Committee of the University of Chicago Library, and is past Vice-Chairman of the Council of The Friends of the Amherst College Library. His personal collection of the works of Samuel Johnson, James Boswell and their circle is among the most complete in private hands in the world. Mr. Ruxin is a frequent speaker before various groups on literary and bibliophilic subjects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Main Library Open House</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32703972</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32703972</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Main Library first floor corridor is open on Commencement Weekend from 1pm - 4pm so students and parents can view the Bronze Tablets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Main Library Open House</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32703973</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32703973</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Main Library first floor corridor is open on Commencement Weekend from 1pm - 4pm so students and parents can view the Bronze Tablets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Poplin and Paper: Four Centuries of Fashion in Print</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32663850</link>
            <category>exhibition</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4092/32663850</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;div class="exhibit"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float: left; margin-right: 25px;" src="http://illinois.edu/cms/2068/barbier_q_792_026b234v_paulette_duval_2785910_web_copy_.gif" alt="George Barbier, vingt-cinc costumes pour le theatre" width="368" height="494" /&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;fashion plate&amp;rdquo; is layered with meanings. It is a portrait depicting not an individual but rather an outfit that a clothier can supply. It is also frequently used to describe someone who wears the latest styles. But a plate is also a printing term, describing an illustration transferred to paper during the printing process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exhibition explores the interdependence between fashion and print to communicate ideas not only about what people wore, but also about those who produced and experienced these images.&amp;nbsp;The exhibition begins with early modern surveys of national costumes, which sought to codify the diverse cultures that Europeans encountered around the world. It then traces emerging interrelationships among fashion plates and the periodical press, commercialism and the performing arts, and the subsequent evolution of various communities of readers and consumers. It culminates in the emergence of fashion photography, a new medium of expression for fashion in print that still shapes its viewers today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Anna Chen, Curator of Rare Books and Manuscripts. The exhibition will be on view Monday through Friday, 8:30am to 5pm, in the Rare Book &amp;amp; Manuscript Library at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>