<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>TCIPG Events</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/4190</link>
        <description>Events sponsored by, coordinated by, or associated with the Trustworthy Cyber Infrastructure for the Power Grid (TCIPG) Center.</description>
        <item>
            <title>2015 TCIPG Summer School</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4190/31823161</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4190/31823161</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="fsl"&gt;The Trustworthy Cyber Infrastructure for the Power Grid (TCIPG) team is excited to offer our fourth summer school, to be held June 15-19, 2015! We invite and encourage utility and industry practitioners, researchers, and students to attend and explore the nexus between electrical energy systems and cybersecurity. Our opening reception will be held on June 14, 2015.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Our summer school program is an intensive, engaging, and value-packed week of integrated learning activities focused on cybersecurity for power and smart grids. The core program emphasizes basics of security and resiliency for cyber infrastructure in power and smart grids. Advanced topics will address the evolving smarter energy system as well as associated cybersecurity challenges. Sessions will offer integrated training exercises using a virtual smart grid environment developed for this school. The week will also offer lightning talks, networking socials, a job/information fair, and extended lab/learning opportunities.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Scholarships and sponsorships available. Advance registration is required. For more information or to register, visit &lt;a href="http://tcipg.org/2015-summer-school" target="_blank" rel="nofollow nofollow"&gt;http://tcipg.org/&lt;wbr /&gt;2015-summer-school&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>