<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Center for Global Studies</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/45</link>
        <description>CGS, a unit of International Programs and Studies, is designated a National Resource Center for the study of globalization under a Title VI grant of the Department of Education. The initiatives and resources of the Center are described in more detail on its home page.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Public talk:  “Ebola in Sierra Leone: A Behavioral Spillover.”</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/45/32701635</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/45/32701635</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Aiah Lebbie, Head of the Department of Biological Sciences at Njala University, will be giving a public talk, titled &amp;ldquo;Ebola in Sierra Leone: A Behavioral Spillover.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Illinois-Njala Global Health Symposium</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/45/32701803</link>
            <category>Other</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/45/32701803</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The keynote speaker is&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Aiah Lebbie&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Njala University in Sierra Leone where he is the head of the Department of Biological Sciences. Dr. Debbie earned his BSc from the University of Sierra Leone in 1989, and his MS in Conservation Biology &amp;amp; Sustainable Development (1995) and PhD in Forest Ecology &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;Management (2001) from the University of Wisconsin-Madison. His research focuses on integrating biological knowledge in addressing conservation/biodiversity issues in Liberia and Sierra Leone with an emphasis on human interactions with tropical ecosystems and understanding social&amp;nbsp;consequences. His research encompasses sacred groves (cultural &amp;amp; biological), ecology of tropical plants and understanding the context in which&amp;nbsp;health, disease, traditional knowledge and medicinal plants converge. He&amp;nbsp;has&amp;nbsp;taught and researched for Njala University College, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Njala University, and the Environment Foundation for Africa.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The symposium will have opening remarks by Dr. Reitumetse Obakeng Mabokela, who is the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign Vice Provost for International Affairs &amp;amp; Global Strategy. In addition, there will be a history of the Illinois-Njala Global Health Partnership, the introduction of the Illinois-Njala Global Health Certificate, and roundtable discussions. Dinner will be provided.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>