<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Urbana Campus Research Calendar</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/4757</link>
        <description>Events related to the research mission of the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.</description>
        <item>
            <title>DAR Financial Planning Town Hall</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32719748</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32719748</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Office of the Vice Chancellor for Research invites your feedback on recommendations to address large deficits in DAR operations. A committee of animal users from across campus was charged with making recommendations to address unsustainable financial shortfalls and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://illinois.edu/cms/secFile/4530/dar_strategic_financial_planning_report__final_.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;final report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;is now available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are invited to share your feedback on this report and provide input on next steps by attending one of the upcoming DAR Town Hall meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, May 12th, 4-5:00 pm, Beckman (2nd Floor Tower Room)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, May 14th, 9-10:00 am, IGB (Conference Room 612)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These meetings are open to all lab animal researchers and members of our research community.&amp;nbsp; If you are unable to attend, please share your comments or suggestions by filling out this form:&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://go.illinois.edu/DAR_Report" target="_blank"&gt;http://go.illinois.edu/DAR_Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Note: This form will close on May 15, 2015.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nobel Laureate Prof. Randy Schekman, University of California at Berkeley, title "Genes and proteins required for secretion of large particles and miRNA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/31747391</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/31747391</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Big Data Hub Informational Meeting</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32712838</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32712838</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Science Foundation is launching a 10-year effort to create partnerships around big data and the management infrastructure for big data. The partnerships and infrastructure are expected to evolve around four regions (South, Northeast, Midwest and West), and NSF is calling for the creation of four Regional Innovation Big Data Hubs. Phase 1 of this effort began with a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2015/nsf15562/nsf15562.htm"&gt;solicitation&lt;/a&gt; in which NSF expects to fund up to four proposals (one from each region).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Illinois is directing the effort for the Midwest Regional Big Data Innovation Hub. NCSA director Ed Seidel and Klara Nahrstedt, director of the Coordinated Science Laboratory, are leading this effort. The Midwest proposal is being written in collaboration with many organizations covering the broad big data challenges of the Midwest, which then academia, industry, foundations, and non-profit organizations can assist to solve. More information will be available as the process unfolds at &lt;a href="https://bdhub.info/"&gt;https://bdhub.info/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nahrstedt and Seidel are seeking knowledge and input for the proposal from University of Illinois researchers who use big data in their domains and who would like to see a broad regional and national alliance develop solutions to the challenges of big data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be two informational meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9-11 am Wednesday, May 13 in the Institute for Genomic Biology, room 612.&lt;/strong&gt; Discussion will address potential faculty participation and contributions in the areas of &lt;strong&gt;Food-Water-Energy Nexus, Genomics, Bioinformatics, Life Sciences, Health Sciences and Digital Agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1-3 pm Thursday, May 21 in the Auditorium of the NCSA Building&lt;/strong&gt;. Topical discussion will be in the areas of &lt;strong&gt;Smart Cities, Advanced Manufacturing, Network Science, Transportation, IT Tools and Services, and Data Science.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Smart Cyberinfrastructure for Big Data Processing</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32702640</link>
            <category>Seminar</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32702640</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 11:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract: &lt;/strong&gt;The landscape of cyberinfrastructure for research is rapidly changing. There is a move towards virtualized and programmable infrastructure. The cloud paradigm enables applications to use computing resources at different places and optimize workflows in either bringing computing to the data or the other way around. Programmable networks allow networks to be utilized in unprecedented ways to create application specific Internets. This talk presents the latest developments in the Research and Education Networks to support Big Data sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio: &lt;/strong&gt;Professor de Laat chairs the System and Network Engineering (SNE) laboratory in the Informatics Institute of the Faculty of Science at University of Amsterdam. Research in his group ranges from optical and switched networking and workflows for processing of big data in PetaScale e-Science applications, Semantic Web to describe e-infrastructure resources, information complexity, Authorization architectures and Systems Security &amp;amp; privacy of information in distributed environments. Prof. de Laat serves on the Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory Policy Board on matters regarding ESnet, is co-founder of the Global Lambda Integrated Facility (GLIF), founder of GRIDforum.nl and founding member of CineGrid.org. His group is/was part of EU projects SWITCH, CYCLONE, ENVRIplus and ENVRI, EuroBrazil, Geysers, NOVI, NEXTGRID, EGEE, and others. He is a member of the Advisory Board Internet Society Netherlands and Scientific technical advisory board of SURF Netherlands. A snapshot of his scientific career is available here: http://delaat.net/.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Big Data Hub Informational Meeting</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32712839</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32712839</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Science Foundation is launching a 10-year effort to create partnerships around big data and the management infrastructure for big data. The partnerships and infrastructure are expected to evolve around four regions (South, Northeast, Midwest and West), and NSF is calling for the creation of four Regional Innovation Big Data Hubs. Phase 1 of this effort began with a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2015/nsf15562/nsf15562.htm"&gt;solicitation&lt;/a&gt; in which NSF expects to fund up to four proposals (one from each region).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Illinois is directing the effort for the Midwest Regional Big Data Innovation Hub. NCSA director Ed Seidel and Klara Nahrstedt, director of the Coordinated Science Laboratory, are leading this effort. The Midwest proposal is being written in collaboration with many organizations covering the broad big data challenges of the Midwest, which then academia, industry, foundations, and non-profit organizations can assist to solve. More information will be available as the process unfolds at &lt;a href="https://bdhub.info/"&gt;https://bdhub.info/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nahrstedt and Seidel are seeking knowledge and input for the proposal from University of Illinois researchers who use big data in their domains and who would like to see a broad regional and national alliance develop solutions to the challenges of big data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be two informational meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9-11 am Wednesday, May 13 in the Institute for Genomic Biology, room 612.&lt;/strong&gt; Discussion will address potential faculty participation and contributions in the areas of &lt;strong&gt;Food-Water-Energy Nexus, Genomics, Bioinformatics, Life Sciences, Health Sciences and Digital Agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1-3 pm Thursday, May 21 in the Auditorium of the NCSA Building&lt;/strong&gt;. Topical discussion will be in the areas of &lt;strong&gt;Smart Cities, Advanced Manufacturing, Network Science, Transportation, IT Tools and Services, and Data Science.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fast Optical Imaging Summer Workshop</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32631635</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32631635</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Optical Imaging Summer School&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Obscura Day: Blue Waters Tour</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32713185</link>
            <category>Special Event</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32713185</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Obscura Day is a global event in which Atlas Obscura celebrates exploration and discovery with more than 150 curious and awe-inspiring real-world expeditions in 35+ states and 20+ countries, all on a single day.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obscura Day is designed to make explorers out of everyone, and to reveal the hidden treasures in your own hometown. This year that includes everything from a sunrise falconry exhibition in the California desert to an excursion to the sacred Hindu caves of Goa Gajah, Bali to a private orchestral performance at the Robotic Church in Brooklyn, and much, much more. The whole roster of events can be found at &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.atlasobscura.com_obscuraday2015&amp;amp;d=AwMFaQ&amp;amp;c=8hUWFZcy2Z-Za5rBPlktOQ&amp;amp;r=r5vA8KQthNivwNDqzwwoFTca94XmJ5-HU3-iT9NiiEw&amp;amp;m=RC1a8zEYBO7GM6JHTLJgX2DLObkejHw-nJsdSSQK3OM&amp;amp;s=BNqHWq8AtK_rbk8ntF_hvVNg4WXoNjfFPN-HQWsC7mM&amp;amp;e="&gt;www.atlasobscura.com/obscuraday2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NCSA is taking part in Obscura Day by offering a tour of the Blue Waters supercomputer, one of the largest and most powerful supercomputers in the world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour begins at 1 pm -- because this is an access-controlled facility, it's important to be prompt (or a little early)! A tour guide will meet you at the front entrance (which is at the corner of Oak and St. Mary's).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Register for the tour in advance at: &lt;a href="http://www.atlasobscura.com/events/obscura-day-2015-behind-the-scenes-at-the-blue-waters-supercomputer"&gt;http://www.atlasobscura.com/events/obscura-day-2015-behind-the-scenes-at-the-blue-waters-supercomputer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>11th Annual CBI TP Symposium: Prof. Laura P.W. Ranum, Univerisity of Florida, "title TBA" &amp; CBI TP Trainees TBD</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32370591</link>
            <category>Symposiums</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32370591</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Looking in the right direction: Carl Woese and the New Biology</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32649928</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32649928</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Carl R. Woese Institute for Genomic Biology is proud to host our symposium "Looking in the right direction: Carl Woese and the New Biology" to mark the renaming of our Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symposium will highlight not only some of the historical aspects of work on microbiology, evolution and molecular biology as researched by Carl Woese and colleagues, but also some of the most exciting modern research directions that have been inspired or impacted by his work and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific program for the event will be held at the &lt;a href="http://www.uiaa.org/alumnicenter/"&gt;Alice Campbell Alumni Center&lt;/a&gt; on the campus of the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Prof. Michael D. Burkart, University of California, San Diego, title "TBA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32710198</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32710198</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dr. John R. Barr, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, title "TBA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32721079</link>
            <category>Seminar</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32721079</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IGB Lewin Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32369965</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32369965</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Sarah A. Tishkoff, PhD from the University of Pennsylvania's Departments of Genetics and Biology will present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IGB Seminar: Guiding Stem Cell Fate for Tissue Engineering Applications via Spatiotemporally Controlled Signal Presentation</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32519919</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32519919</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 12:00:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Eben Alsberg, PhD from&amp;nbsp;Case Western Reserve University's&amp;nbsp;Department of Biomedical Engineering will present "Guiding Stem Cell Fate for Tissue Engineering Applications via Spatiotemporally Controlled Signal Presentation."&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IGB Genome Day 2015</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32171934</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32171934</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 13:00:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Genome Day is an opportunity for the community to learn about DNA, genes, genomes, and evolution at the Orpheum Children&amp;rsquo;s Science Museum. Activities will be designed to present the energy use and production, environment, health, and fundamental research at the Institute for Genomic Biology in an approachable manner for all ages. Admission to the event and museum will be free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Prof. David G. Lynn, Emory University, title "TBA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32701632</link>
            <category>Academic</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32701632</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 16:00:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Prof. David G. Lynn, Emory University, title "TBA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32701633</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/4757/32701633</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 16:00:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>