<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Campus Humanities Calendar</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/5093</link>
        <description>Humanities Calendar</description>
        <item>
            <title>Panel Discussion of AAUP Censure and the University of Illinois</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32700955</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32700955</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 14:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;The Annual Meeting of the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Chapter of the American Association of University Professors will be Tuesday, May 12 in the Illini Union 209-211. All are welcome.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;A social hour will start at 2:30 p.m. in 211 Illini Union. Around 3 p.m., we will move next door into Illini Union 209 to start the formal program with a brief Business Meeting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;This will be followed by a panel discussion on AAUP censure and the University of Illinois. There will be time for questions and discussion. All are welcome to attend and join the discussion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Moderator: Harry Hilton, Chapter President&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Panelists: David OBrien, Art and Design, How Did We Get Here?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Cary Nelson, English, What Can the University Do?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OVCR: ACLS, Fulbright, and Residential Fellowships Information Session</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32636211</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32636211</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;The session offers an overview of these fellowship and grant competitions. In anticipation of fall application deadlines, we will provide application-related materials. Recent fellowship recipients will discuss their experiences with the application process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Molly Melching: "Development from the Inside Out"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32706142</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32706142</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Molly will discuss a recent visit to Eastern Senegal, where she found the community members, particularly women and youth, totally engaged in promoting human rights, as well as women and youth leadership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;She will then explain the Tostan program and the reasons behind its success. Tostan is a US-registered 501c international nongovernmental organization with current operations in over 450 communities in Senegal, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, The Gambia, Mali, and Mauritania. Its mission is to empower African communities to bring about sustainable development and positive social transformation based on respect for human rights.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Molly will also touch on social norm theory, which has informed the work of program members during the past 15 years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Biography - Molly Melching, a graduate of the University of Illinois (AB 71, general curriculum; MA 79, French), has lived and worked in Senegal, West Africa, since 1974 and has dedicated her life to the empowerment of communities at the grassroots level.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;While on campus, Molly will receive the 2015 University of Illinois Humanitarian Award. This prestigious award is presented to graduates whose outstanding leadership and service have significantly enriched the lives of others and the welfare of humanity. Melching was chosen for the honor by her fellow alumni/ae. She will receive the award during the campus-wide Commencement ceremony on Saturday, May 16.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slcl.illinois.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2015-16 Reading Group Submissions Due</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32650777</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32650777</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;"&gt;The Illinois Program for Research in the Humanities invites applications from continuing and new Reading Groups for the 2015&amp;ndash;16 academic year. Reading Groups may be formed around any topic or theme; they need not be coordinated with the IPRH theme for this or any other year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;IPRH is also pleased to offer our seminar space for use by those groups that would like to meet in the IPRH building. Each Reading Group will be wholly responsible for its own administration, including all clerical and meeting-related activities and the distribution of readings and publicity materials. IPRH will make its facilities available for use by the Reading Groups, who shall be responsible for scheduling all facility use in advance with the IPRH staff; all scheduling will be based on availability. IPRH will also publish meeting and event information for Reading Groups on the &lt;a href="http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/5016"&gt;Reading Group &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;Research Cluster Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;found on IPRH's website.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading Groups wishing to be included in the IPRH publicity materials must submit the following information no later than May 15, 2015:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;The names, departmental affiliations, and e-mail addresses of the group&amp;rsquo;s organizers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;A short statement (maximum 75 words) describing the goals of the group and a brief outline of the proposed activities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://illinois.edu/fb/sec/2816475" target="_blank"&gt;Please submit all information using our Reading Group submission&amp;nbsp;form.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Faculty Publications Submissions for Humanities Showcase Due</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32669713</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32669713</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;This summer, IPRH&amp;nbsp;will publish a list of faculty publications in&amp;nbsp;the "&lt;a href="https://illinois.edu/emailer/forward?emailId=71980&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.iprh.illinois.edu%2Fresources%2Fshowcase%2Fpublications.html&amp;amp;emailAddress=&amp;amp;factsReferenceId=0"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Humanities Showcase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"&amp;nbsp;section of&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;IPRH website.&amp;nbsp;As you know, our faculty have a very active record of publication, which we aim to celebrate. In order to render the list&lt;span class="s1"&gt;manageable for web&amp;nbsp;navigation,&lt;/span&gt; we are a&lt;span class="s1"&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;loting&lt;strong&gt; three entries per professor&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;nbsp;If you would like your&amp;nbsp;work to appear in the web listing, please select the (up to)&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;three&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;publication&lt;/strong&gt;s you would most like to highlight among those&lt;span class="s1"&gt;you&amp;rsquo;ve&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;published in the 2014-15 academic year. Please note that forthcoming publications are not eligible for inclusion this&amp;nbsp;round.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;P&lt;/span&gt;lease send&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;nbsp;your&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;up to&amp;nbsp;three&amp;nbsp;citations for &lt;span class="s1"&gt;2014-15&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;publications, along&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;an indication of your departmental affiliation(s) beyond 0%, &lt;span class="s1"&gt;in the body of an email &lt;/span&gt;to Kelly Delahanty&amp;nbsp;(&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:iprh_coordinator@mx.uillinois.edu"&gt;iprh_coordinator@mx.uillinois.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) at the IPRH&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;by&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;, May 30, 2015,&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;using the format listed below.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;For&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;foreign-language citations,&amp;nbsp;please&amp;nbsp;send those in a Word document attachment as well (important&amp;nbsp;formatting is often lost when these are cut/pasted directly into email messages). &lt;span class="s1"&gt;We regret that limited staff time prevents us from culling information from&amp;nbsp;CVs&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;annual reports, so we ask your cooperation in kindly refraining from forwarding them in lieu of the&amp;nbsp;information&amp;nbsp;requested.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation format for publications&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;(We understand that your faculty may need to use alternate formats):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;(in bold).&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Publication Title&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;(in italics). Publisher, place of publication, and date (regular).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;**For journal articles please include the relevant volume, issue number, and page numbers. Electronic publications must be accompanied by the appropriate URL.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>RFP: American Academy in Rome Invites Applications for Rome Prize</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32647587</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32647587</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 08:30:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;A program of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.aarome.org/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;American Academy in Rome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Rome Prize is awarded North American to thirty emerging artists and scholars in the early or middle stages of their careers who exemplify the highest standard of excellence in arts and humanities scholarship.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Fellows are chosen from the disciplines of architecture, design, historic preservation and conservation, landscape architecture, literature, musical composition, visual arts, ancient studies, Medieval studies, Renaissance and Early Modern studies, and Modern Italian studies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Each Rome Prize winner is provided with a stipend, meals, a bedroom with private bath, and a study or studio. (Those with children under the age of 18 live in partially subsidized apartments nearby.) Winners of six-month and eleven-month fellowships receive stipends of $16,000 and $28,000, respectively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Applicants for all Rome Prize fellowships, except those applying for the National Endowment for the Humanities postdoctoral fellowship, must be citizens of the United States at the time of the application. U.S citizens and foreign nationals who have lived in the U.S. for three years immediately preceding the application deadline may apply for an NEH postdoctoral fellowship. Graduate students in the humanities may apply only for pre-doctoral fellowships. Previous winners of the Rome Prize are not eligible to re-apply. Undergraduate students are not eligible for Rome Prize fellowships.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Fee required&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Visit the American Academy in Rome Web site for complete program guidelines and application instructions: &lt;a href="http://www.aarome.org/apply/rome-prize/procedure-requirements" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Complete RFP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline&lt;/strong&gt;: November 1, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Deadline: IPRH Faculty and Graduate Student Campus Fellowship application</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32682901</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/5093/32682901</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 23:55:00 CST</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt;"&gt;Learn more about IPRH faculty and graduate student campus fellowships at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.iprh.illinois.edu/fellowships/campus/index.html"&gt;iprh.illinois.edu/fellowships/campus/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>