<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Speakers</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/598</link>
        <description>This is the Speakers calendar for the Urbana-Champaign campus at the University of Illinois.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Nobel Laureate Prof. Randy Schekman, University of California at Berkeley, title "Genes and proteins required for secretion of large particles and miRNA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/31747391</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/31747391</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Condensed Matter Special Seminar:</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32723393</link>
            <category>CM Seminar</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32723393</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707105</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707105</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707110</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707110</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2015 Ralph and Ruth Fisher Forum: Violence in Twenthieth-Century Russia and Eurasia: Experience, Affect, Memory, and Legacies</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32370575</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32370575</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;VIOLENCE IN TWENTIETH-CENTURY RUSSIA AND EURASIA: EXPERIENCE, AFFECT, MEMORY, AND LEGACIES&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;June 19-20, 2015&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian, East European, and Eurasian Center&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organized by Harriet Murav and Mark Steinberg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a poem dedicated to the memory of 19 June 1914, Anna Akhmatova wrote &amp;quot;we aged a hundred years and this / Happened in a single hour.&amp;quot; The twentieth century brought unprecedented violence to the European world, not least in the Russian Empire and the Soviet Union. The years 1914-1921, among the most bloody and destructive in Russia's history, cannot be understood in isolation from the whole jagged landscape of violence - international wars, violent political force, national and revolutionary violence, ethnic and racial violence, interpersonal and domestic violence. Boundaries do not easily stand in violent conditions. Emancipatory and repressive violence mix and blur. Purposeful political and social struggles mix with &amp;quot;hooliganism&amp;quot; and commonplace human brutality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And violence itself is only part of the story. The twentieth century, especially its first decades, saw a remarkable explosion of creativity in the arts, literature, science, politics, philosophy, and social organization, as well as extraordinary technological innovation and invention. Indeed, violence itself could be understood in radically different ways, including as creativity, even as actions in the name of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2015 Fisher Forum will examine the immediacy, effects, and refractions of violence in Russia and Eurasia (defined as the spaces occupied by the Russian Empire and the Soviet Union) from perspective across disciplines. Papers will also engage the question of how to interpret and theorize violence, as practice, as experience, as legacy. Indeed, while our focus is on the past, we cannot ignore lasting effects and persistent meanings, including for our own time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LIST OF PARTICIPANTS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please also see: http://www.reeec.illinois.edu/events/conferences/2015FisherForum.html&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707111</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707111</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707113</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707113</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707117</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707117</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Noontime Scholars Lecture</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707128</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32707128</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IGB Pollen Power Camp</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32219929</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32219929</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Hosted by the Institute for Genomic Biology on the University of Illinois campus, the camp will provide an opportunity for girls to study plant responses to climate change in the distant past and the coming century. Research groups of 8 to 10 campers led by a female graduate student will use million-dollar microscopes to image pollen, giving the campers first-hand experience in a research environment with female mentors. The camp is designed for girls who have completed 6th or 7th grade, or are entering 7th or 8th grade in the Fall 2015, and who have an interest in plants and the environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IGB Pioneers Seminar: Opportunities and Pitfalls in Translating Promising Medical Concepts to the Marketplace</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32630942</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32630942</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Arthur J. Coury,&amp;nbsp;Department of Chemical Engineering at&amp;nbsp;Northeastern University in Boston, will present for IGB's Pioneers Seminar on, "Opportunities and Pitfalls in Translating Promising Medical Concepts to the Marketplace."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>11th Annual CBI TP Symposium: Prof. Laura P.W. Ranum, Univerisity of Florida, "title TBA" &amp; CBI TP Trainees TBD</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32370591</link>
            <category>Symposiums</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32370591</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>INHS Seminar - TBD</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32610057</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32610057</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>IGB Seminar: Title to be Announced</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32630943</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32630943</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 12:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Susanne von Bodman, PhD&lt;br /&gt;National Science Foundation&lt;br /&gt;Program Director, Cluster Leader&lt;br /&gt;Systems and Synthetic Biology Cluster&lt;br /&gt;Division of Molecular and Cellular Biosciences&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>INHS Seminar - TBD</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32610058</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32610058</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 15:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>G.F. Smith Memorial Lecture, Professor Christian Amatore-Ecole Normale Superieure-Paris "TBA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32294078</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32294078</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>G.F. Smith Memorial Lecture, Professor Christian Amatore- Ecole Normale Superieure- Paris- "TBA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32294080</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32294080</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Looking in the right direction: Carl Woese and the New Biology</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32649928</link>
            <category></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32649928</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Carl R. Woese Institute for Genomic Biology is proud to host our symposium "Looking in the right direction: Carl Woese and the New Biology" to mark the renaming of our Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symposium will highlight not only some of the historical aspects of work on microbiology, evolution and molecular biology as researched by Carl Woese and colleagues, but also some of the most exciting modern research directions that have been inspired or impacted by his work and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific program for the event will be held at the &lt;a href="http://www.uiaa.org/alumnicenter/"&gt;Alice Campbell Alumni Center&lt;/a&gt; on the campus of the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Familiar Strangers: The Georgian Diaspora and the Evolution of Soviet Empire</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32706929</link>
            <category>Lecture</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32706929</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the history of Georgians beyond the Georgian republic from 1917 to the present, this presentation explores the rise and fall of the Soviet multiethnic empire from the perspective of its most prominent internal diaspora. Joseph Stalin (Jughashvili) was just one of a group of Georgian revolutionaries who came to power in the early years of Soviet rule and directed the development of the new state. After the socialist state was established, Soviet citizens sought new opportunities for leisure and consumption and found them at the Georgian restaurant, where they adopted the distinctive rituals of the Georgian table. During Khrushchev&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Thaw,&amp;rdquo; Georgian cultural entrepreneurs embodied the era&amp;rsquo;s spirit of spontaneity as popular ethnic entertainers specializing in song, dance, and theater. As official life grew stagnant under Brezhnev, Georgians thrived in the burgeoning informal economy. Finally, with the advent of Gorbachev&amp;rsquo;s reforms, it was a Georgian film, &lt;em&gt;Repentance&lt;/em&gt;, that explored the furthest limits of allowable expression, calling into question the very legitimacy of Soviet power. The prominence of the Georgian diaspora suggests that the Soviet Union was not simply a Russian empire, nor merely a multiethnic state composed of separate nations; instead, it was an empire of diasporas, where politics, culture, and economics were constituted by the mixing of a diverse array of mobile nationalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erik R. Scott&lt;/strong&gt; is Assistant Professor of Russian and Soviet history at the University of Kansas. Drawing on years of fieldwork and knowledge of several regional languages, his research and teaching explore migration and diaspora within and beyond the imperial borders of Russia and Eurasia. His book, &lt;em&gt;Familiar Strangers: The Georgian Diaspora and the Multiethnic Soviet Empire &lt;/em&gt;(forthcoming from Oxford University Press in 2016), reimagines the Soviet empire by revealing how external borders concealed an array of specialized internal diaspora populations. He has recently begun a new project on Soviet defectors and the production of Cold War borders, focusing in particular on the winding journeys of defectors through border zones, transit hubs, extraterritorial spaces, and contested areas beyond the limits of state jurisdiction. He teaches undergraduate and graduate courses on Russian and Soviet history, the Cold War, comparative empires, and migration in global perspective. He received his Ph.D. from the University of California, Berkeley in 2011 and was the Post-Doctoral Fellow in Caucasian and Central Asian Affairs at Georgetown University&amp;rsquo;s Center for Eurasian, Russian, and East European Studies from 2011 to 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Prof. Michael D. Burkart, University of California, San Diego, title "TBA"</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32710200</link>
            <category>Seminar</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/598/32710200</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 16:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>