<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Staff Training</title>
        <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/list/642</link>
        <description>Training and workshops calendar for the Urbana campus at the University of Illinois.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Dreamweaver CC: Level 2</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32566119</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32566119</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small; font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"&gt;The Dreamweaver Level 2 workshop explores CSS in much greater depth, and also covers a number of Dreamweaver "power features" that add greatly to the richness and productivity of the program. You'll learn to effectively control the layout and format of your web pages on multiple devices (desktop, tablet, and/or phone) with Dreamweaver&amp;rsquo;s powerful CSS-based &amp;ldquo;fluid grid layout&amp;rdquo; tools. You'll use CSS to format your pages, create CSS &amp;ldquo;rollover&amp;rdquo; transitions, and create web forms to collect and validate data (for example, double-checking email address entries). You'll also include audio and video files on your pages, as well as integrating Photoshop files into web pages, with automatic conversion to browser-compatible formats. Finally, you'll preview and test your web site for browser compatibility, CSS validation, basic accessibility features, and much more. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prerequisite:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp; Dreamweaver Level 1 workshop, or equivalent knowledge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>PowerPoint 2013: Level 2</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500277</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500277</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This 6-hour course is designed to help users prepare more effective presentations using PowerPoint 2013. Upon successful completion of this course, students will be able to customize the PowerPoint 2013 environment, customize a design template, work with SmartArt graphics, media and animations, and customize a slide show. &amp;nbsp;Collaboration tools will also be explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisite: Completion of PowerPoint 2013 Level 1 or equivalent knowledge&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Microsoft Operating System and Software Updates</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/31920842</link>
            <category>Personal</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/31920842</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 08:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft regularly releases updates for all versions of Windows, Office and other Microsoft applications. Using Internet Explorer visit: &lt;a href="http://update.microsoft.com"&gt; http://update.microsoft.com &lt;/a&gt; to receive these important updates today. For more information on securing your operating system please visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://security.illinois.edu/content/securing-your-computer"&gt;https://security.illinois.edu/content/securing-your-computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Outlook 2013: People &amp; Tasks</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500278</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500278</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 10:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a contact in Outlook 2013 can save you time when sending an email message and using Lync. Once you've entered a name as a contact, you can add business or personal information such as phone numbers and addresses. In this 2-hour short course you will learn how to work in the People window to add a new contact (manually and from a received email message); change contacts view; use color categories to organize your contacts; search for a contact; and print a contacts list. We will also look at contact groups (email distribution lists).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tasks features of Outlook 2013 help you create lists of task-related items. We will look at the different views in the Task window; we will add tasks (including recurring tasks); attach items to a task; assign and track a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisite: Completion of Outlook 2010 Email Fundamentals or equivalent knowledge. &amp;nbsp;A Microsoft Exchange account is required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Illustrator CC/CS6: Level 2</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32566120</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32566120</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover some of Illustrator&amp;rsquo;s more advanced capabilities for creating even more sophisticated and striking results. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn to create custom shapes and &amp;ldquo;compound paths&amp;rdquo; using simple shapes as a starting point, to create perspective drawings using Illustrator&amp;rsquo;s Perspective Grid tool, and to use Illustrator's newly enhanced "image trace" feature to convert (simple) photographs into fully-scalable Illustrator paths. You'll also work with colors, swatches, Pantone libraries, and color groups, create custom brushes, and use Illustrator's "Live Paint" feature, as well as painting objects with fills, strokes, and gradients. &amp;nbsp;Other topics include advanced type formatting options, applying meshes, patterns, transparency, and blending modes to objects, as well as working with graphics styles and effects, masks, symbol sets, symbolism tools, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Word 2013: Level 1</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500280</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500280</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This six-hour course is intended for those who want to learn basic Word 2013 skills such as creating, editing, and formatting documents; inserting simple tables and creating lists; and employing a variety of techniques for improving the appearance and accuracy of document content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lync 2013: What's New?</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500281</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500281</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 10:30:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;In this 1.5-hour overview, we will explore the new look and feel of Lync 2013 including the Quick Lync bar which provides more functionality with a cleaner look. Working with contacts is easier than ever using the new Favorites group to build a list of people you contact the most often. We will tour the ways to view your contacts list including &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; to see a list of people who have asked to be included on your Contacts list. We&amp;rsquo;ll see where the Chat Rooms feature has replaced the Activity Feed view. The New Tabbed Conversation feature is next, where you can keep all your calls, instant messages, and chat rooms in one conversation window. Interface changes also include icons at the bottom of the conversation window which let you quickly add others to an IM or upgrade to an audio call, a video call, or a presentation with file-sharing and web conferencing tools (whiteboard, meeting notes, shared notebooks, and attachments). We will practice making calls and sending messages using this new interface. Lastly, we will try out the new Video features including the new Gallery View, where you can automatically see everyone in a video conference.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prerequisite:&amp;nbsp; An activated Lync account is required (&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.go.illinois.edu/myuc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.go.illinois.edu/myuc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to check account status before attending)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Graduate Contacts: Partnership for Success Workshop: CPT/OPT/AT</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32227687</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32227687</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 11:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Graduate College Faculty/Staff Training&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lync 2013: Audio/Video/Web Conferencing</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500282</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500282</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;This two hour workshop will demonstrate how easy it is to set up and attend an online meeting using Lync 2013. Meeting schedulers will learn how to escalate an instant message or phone conversation into an audio or video conference; schedule an online meeting in Outlook 2010 or 2013 using default options; customize advanced meeting options for unique meeting requirements; how to create a recording of a meeting; and schedule a meeting on behalf of another. Different meeting roles (attendee versus presenter) will be discussed; and we will learn how to use a virtual waiting room known as a &amp;ldquo;lobby&amp;rdquo; for control over who attends a meeting. In addition, we&amp;rsquo;ll spend a few minutes looking at the new expanded meeting controls including the Share menu which gives you access to all presentable content in one place, such as Desktop, PowerPoint presentations, Poll, Whiteboard, and OneNote. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at the new meeting layouts for different types of meetings. We will learn about Lync Web App which allows PC and Mac users to join a Lync Meeting from within a web browser while delivering a full Lync Meeting experience. Finally, the use of Lync Mobile clients will be discussed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 8pt;"&gt;Prerequisite: An activated Lync account is required (www.go.illinois.edu/myuc to check account status before attending)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Outlook 2013: Tips and Tricks</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500283</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500283</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 10:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Wish you had a smarter, more efficient way to arrange your Outlook 2013 email? In this two-hour workshop, you will learn how to use the conversation view; how to insert a screenshot into a message; sorting messages; advanced searching techniques, including filters; working with folders; using flags, color categories, and rules.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Excel 2013: Level 2</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500284</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500284</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In this 6-hour Excel 2013 Level 2 course, you will create advanced formulas; analyze data with logical and lookup functions; organize worksheet data with tables; visualize data by using charts; and analyze data with PivotTables, slicers, and PivotCharts. &amp;nbsp;This course is about one simple idea: asking your data questions and using Excel 2013 to find the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisite: Completion of Excel 2013 Level 1 or equivalent knowledge&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OneNote 2013: Basics</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500285</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500285</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In this 3 hour course, you will develop digital note-taking, note-collaboration, and note-synchronizing skills with OneNote 2013. Topics covered will include: exploring the structure of a OneNote notebook; adding content to and organize a OneNote notebook; managing OneNote notebooks, history, and backups; working with Excel spreadsheets and embedded files; sharing and collaborate with notebooks; and finalizing a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lync 2011: Basics for Mac users</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500286</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32500286</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 10:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Lync 2011 provides a single interface on your computer that unites voice communications, instant messaging, and audio/video conferencing all at once. In this 2-hour hands-on instructor led workshop, attendees will learn how to start and sign on to Lync, learn how to navigate the Lync 2011 program window, learn about presence (availability status), add contacts to their contact list, and find help resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next attendees will learn how to use the voice and video features of Lync, including how to adjust audio settings, how to make and receive a phone call, a conference call, and a video call. Attendees will practice transferring and forwarding calls. Instant messaging is another form of communication in Lync. Attendees will learn how to start an instant message, how to reply, and how to format text in an instant message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees will experience sharing their desktop or program window with someone else and see how easy it is to share files using Lync. Finally, the integration between Microsoft Outlook 2011 for the Mac and Lync 2011 will be explored, including how easy it is to communicate with others from within an email message or calendar event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Illinois Compass 2g: The Basics Online</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32483736</link>
            <category>Demonstration and Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32483736</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 10:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;CITES now offers an online training workshop for Illinois Compass 2g (powered by Blackboard Learn). In this one-hour workshop attendees will learn basic features and functions of Illinois Compass 2g including customization, organization, and design of the course space. This workshop will cover select teaching tools including Student Preview, Announcements, Assignments, and the Grade Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This online workshop will be delivered in the CITES Virtual Office which uses Blackboard Collaborate. The URL to join the demonstration is: &lt;a href="http://go.illinois.edu/CITESVirtualOffice"&gt;http://go.illinois.edu/CITESVirtualOffice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend that registrants visit the URL below at least a day before the session to ensure that their system is compatible with Blackboard Collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://go.illinois.edu/collabcheck"&gt;http://go.illinois.edu/collabcheck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration: 1 hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event type: Workshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event sponsor(s): CITES Academic Technology Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download Workshop Materials:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Compass 2g Resources and Links" href="https://uofi.box.com/ic2gresources"&gt;Compass 2g Resources and Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>SharePoint Designer 2013</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669516</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669516</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;Starting in January 2015, the SharePoint 2010 shared service at the University of Illinois will migrate to version 2013. SharePoint Designer is the free no-code development software used for site customization and development. Now is the time to become familiar with the new development interface and features of SharePoint Designer 2013.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;In this 7-hour course we will learn about and create custom site columns and content types, connections that bring external data from a database, XML or web services into a site, data source views and how to use the new workflow platform. The new Visual Designer interface for workflows now leverages the graphical power of Visio 2013. We will use it to create workflow stages, steps and loops and learn how to publish, package and deploy workflows for distribution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pre-requisite: Familiarity with site design using the graphical web interface is assumed. No previous with SharePoint Designer is needed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Computer Security Training</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/31911374</link>
            <category>Training</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/31911374</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Office of Privacy and Information Assurance (OPIA) is pleased to offer a Security Orientation for faculty and staff. Attendees will learn how to secure their computers, proper password management, IT security policies, how to protect sensitive University data, and how to protect their personal identity information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Working with Sensitive Data Training</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/31911375</link>
            <category>Training</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/31911375</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 14:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Office of Privacy and Information Assurance (OPIA) is pleased to offer an orientation for faculty and staff that work with sensitive data. Attendees will learn about how to protect sensitive data, securely share data with other people, and how to safely store or destroy data once they are done using it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>MS Office Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669517</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669517</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 09:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Unleash your Microsoft Office Super Powers!&amp;nbsp; No matter what version of Office you are using--2010 or 2013--you will not want to miss this half-day workshop covering exciting document solutions in Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Publisher, and Word.&amp;nbsp; Topics covered will include learning how to create name tents; customized name tags; copy design templates to a new PowerPoint presentation; create and send an e-newsletter; create a multi-sheet Excel workbook with formulas in under 5 minutes; and much more. The time spent in this workshop will be recovered many times over after learning these time-saving tips &amp;amp; tricks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisite:&amp;nbsp; familiarity with Windows and Office applications&lt;br /&gt;Length:&amp;nbsp; 3 hours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Excel 2013: Getting Started</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669518</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669518</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 10:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: medium; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: auto; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: auto; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; display: inline !important; float: none;"&gt;In this 2-hour short course you will learn how to comfortably move around in the Excel 2013 environment. Additional topics will include entering text and values in a worksheet, basic formatting, printing and using Help.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OneNote 2013: Basics</title>
            <link>http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669519</link>
            <category>Workshop</category>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://illinois.edu/calendar/detail/642/32669519</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 13:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In this 3 hour course, you will develop digital note-taking, note-collaboration, and note-synchronizing skills with OneNote 2013. Topics covered will include: exploring the structure of a OneNote notebook; adding content to and organize a OneNote notebook; managing OneNote notebooks, history, and backups; working with Excel spreadsheets and embedded files; sharing and collaborate with notebooks; and finalizing a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>